逍 遥 法 外 / 猫 鼠 游 戏
非常感谢
Thank you very much
欢迎各位来到《真真假假》
and welcome to To Tell the Truth.
我们的第一位客人  他让自己成为
Our first guest, he's made a career
最无耻的以冒名顶替为生的骗子
out of being the most outrageous impostor
是我们这个节目从未邀请过的
that we've ever come across on this show
你很快就会明白我的意思的
and you're going to see what I mean.
1号选手  请问你叫什么名字?
Number One what is your name, please?
我叫弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔
My name is Frank William Abagnale.
2号选手呢?
Number Two?
我叫弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔
My name is Frank William Abagnale.
3号选手呢?
Number Three?
我叫弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔
My name is Frank William Abagnale.
从1964年到1967年...
"From 1964 to 1967
我成功地冒充了  泛美航空公司的 飞行员
"I successfully impersonated "an airline pilot for Pan Am Airways
免费飞了3百多万公里
"and I flew over two million miles for free.
那段时间  我是乔治亚州一家医院的
"During that time, I was also the chief resident pediatrician
儿科见习医生主管
"at a Georgia hospital
还是路易斯安那州首席检察官的一名助理
"and an assistant attorney general "for the state of Louisiana.
在我被逮捕时   我被认为是
"By the time I was caught, I was considered
美国历史上  最年轻及最胆大的骗子
"the youngest and most daring con man in U.s. history.
我在美国境外的26个国家  和境内的50个州里...
"I had cashed almost $4 million in fraudulent checks
用伪造的支票套取了约4百万美元的现金
"in 26 foreign countries and all 50 states.
而所有这些都是在我19岁生日之前做的
"And I did it all before my 19th birthday.
我叫弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔
My name is Frank William Abagnale."
他要讲真话了
So, for the first time he's gonna have to tell the truth
首先由基蒂发问
and we're going to start our questioning with Kitty.
谢谢  1号选手  凭你的聪明才智
Thank you. Number One, why, with all your talent...
你肯定是个非常聪明的家伙
and you're obviously a very bright fellow...
你为什么不找个合法的职业谋生?
why didn't you go in for a legitimate profession?
这是个挣钱多少的问题
It was really a question of dollars and cents.
年轻的时候的时候  我需要钱...
When I was a young man, I needed the money
我想这个职业  是最简单的挣钱方法
and I thought this list of careers was the easiest way to get it.
明白了
I see.
2号选手  我发现这真奇妙
Number Two, I find this all very fascinating.
是谁最后抓住你的?
Who was it that finally caught you?
他叫卡尔·汉莱提
His name was Carl Handratty.
汉-莱-提
Han-an-an-ratty.
莱提
Ratty.
汉莱提
Handratty.
Han-ratty.
卡尔·汉莱提
Carl Handratty.
- 是的  - 我...
-Yes. -I...
叫...卡尔·汉莱提
am... Carl Handratty.
我代表美国的联邦调查局
I represent the FBI from the United states of America.
我有官方许可
Yeah. I have orders
来见那个美国囚犯  阿巴戈内尔
to see the American prisoner, Abagnale.
法国  马赛  1969年圣诞节前夕
你坐在这里
You sit here.
不许开这扇门
You do not open the door.
不许从这个小孔
You do not pass him...
递给他任何东西
anything through the hole.
天啊
Aw... Jesus.
你知道  我自己也有点感冒了
You know, I've got a little bit of a cold myself.
弗兰克
Frank...
按照欧洲人权法...
I'm here to read the articles of extradition...
我来宣读引渡条例
according to the European Court for Human Rights.
第1款: 引渡将被批准...
Article One: Extradition shall be granted
关于犯下按照法律应受惩罚罪行...
in respect of offenses punishable under the laws..."
- 救我  - 最长期限至少一年的
- help me. - for the maximum period of at least one year
严厉刑法
of a severe penalty.
救我
Help me.
弗兰克...  住口
Frank... stop it.
救我
Help me.
你没想骗我  是吧?
You don't think actually you can fool me, do you?
还有16页没读完呢  注意听
16 pages to go. stay with me.
第2款:
Article Two:
"如果引渡请求中  包含了几种不同的罪名...
"If the request for extradition "includes several separate offenses
而其中的每一项都可以进行判罪..."
each of which is punishable under the laws..."
"根据 请求方的法律..."
"of the requesting party..."
弗兰克?
Frank?
他妈的!
Goddamn it!
快找医生来!
Get me a doctor in here!
- 我需要名医生!  - 是的
- I need a doctor! -Yes.
医生!  现在就要!
Doctor! Now!
别紧张  弗兰克  我们带你去医生那儿
Don't sweat it, Frank. We're going to get you right to a doctor.
弗兰克  如果你能听见我  别担心
Frank, if you can hear me, don't worry.
我明天早晨就带你回美国
I'm going to take you home in the morning.
明天早晨  弗兰克
Home in the morning, Frank.
- 你在做什么?  - 洗掉虱子
- What are you doing? - Washing off the lice.
要尽快送这个人上飞机  他需要医生
This man has to be on a plane for America. He has to see a doctor.
医生明天来
The doctor comes in tomorrow.
我花那么大的功夫才抓住他
I have worked too long, too hard
不是为了让你胡来
for you to take this away from me.
如果他死了  你负责
If he dies, I'm holding you responsible.
先生
Monsieur!
弗兰克
Ah, Frank.
好吧  卡尔...
Okay, Carl...
我们回美国吧
let's go home.
新罗谢尔·罗特瑞俱乐部...
The New Rochelle Rotary Club
的历史可以追述到1919
has a history that goes back to 1919.
在这些年中...
In all those years
只有少数几位先生
we've only seen a handful of deserving gentlemen
被荣幸接纳为终身会员
inducted as lifetime members.
那是一种荣誉
It's an honor that, uh
现已有57个名字铭记在这荣誉之墙上了
that has seen 57 names enshrined on the wall of honor
今晚  我们会产生第58位
and tonight, we make it 58:
请起立  让我来介绍我的好朋友
so please stand as I present my very good friend
一个总是把我们的铅笔磨尖...
a man who keeps our pencils sharp...
把我们的钢笔充满墨水的人
and our pens in ink...
弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔
Frank William Abagnale.
我很谦卑的站在
I stand here humbled
罗伯特·瓦格纳市长...
by the presence of Mayor Robert Wagner...
及我们的俱乐部主席杰克·巴恩斯的旁边
and our club president, Jack Barnes.
最想说的就是 我荣幸地看见我的太太保拉...
Most of all, I'm honored to see my loving wife Paula...
和我的儿子小弗兰克...
and my son, Frank Jr...
弗兰克...  站起来  快点...
Frank... Aw, stand up. Come on...
他坐在第一排
sitting in the front row.
两只小老鼠掉进了一桶奶油中
Two little mice fell in a bucket of cream.
第一只很快就放弃了  然后被淹死了
The first mouse quickly gave up and drowned.
第二只...  没有放弃.
The second mouse... wouldn't quit.
他努力的挣扎着...
He struggled so hard
最终他竟把奶油搅混成了黄油
that eventually he churned that cream into butter
然后爬了出来
and crawled out.
先生们  此刻  我就是那第二只老鼠
Gentlemen, as of this moment, I am that second mouse.
你跳舞跳得比你爸还好  弗兰克
You're a better dancer than your father, Frankie.
- 你听到了吗  爸爸?  - 开玩笑
- You hear that, Daddy? - Like fun.
女孩们不知道她们这是为了什么
The girls don't know what they're in for.
给他展示一下我们见面时你跳舞的样子
show him the dance you were doing when we met.
谁能记得住?
Ah, who can remember?
那个法国小村庄的人
The people in that little French village
非常高兴见到美国人
were so happy to see Americans
他们决定给我们表演一场
they decided to put on a show for us.
- 所以挤进来200个士兵  - 我们知道那个故事
- so they crammed 200 soldiers... - Yeah, we know the story, Daddy.
挤到那个小活动厅里
into that tiny social hall
而第一个上台的
and the first person to walk onstage
就是你母亲  她开始跳舞
is your mother, and she starts to dance.
你知道  我们当时有几个月没见过女人了
You know, it had been months since we'd even seen a woman
而这有位金发天使
and here's this blonde angel.
金发美人
Blonde bombshell.
那些男人都摒住了呼吸
And the men are literally holding their breath.
为你摒住了呼吸  你听见了吗?
Holding their breath for you. You hear that?
我转过去对我的朋友们说...
And I turned to my buddies and I said...
"不得到她我决不离开法国"
"I will not leave France without her."
而我真没离开
And I didn't.
你没离开
You didn't.
我没离开
I didn't.
该死的  地毯
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, the rug!
妈...
Aw, Mom...
我真不敢相信我做的
I can't believe I did that.
没关系  没关系
No, no, it's nothing. It's nothing.
弗兰基  快去找毛巾
Oh, Frankie, Frankie, get a towel.
- 保拉  没事的  - 好  好
- Paula... Come on. - Yeah, yeah.
和我跳支舞  保拉
Dance with me, Paula.
无论什么时候跟你跳舞  我都会惹麻烦
Whenever I dance for you i get in trouble.
看这
Watch this.
弗兰克!  醒醒  快点  要走了
Frank! Wake up. Come on, let's go!
快点  快点起来
Get up. Come on, come on.
弗兰克  醒醒
Frank, wake up.
老爸
Dad.
你今天不用去上学  没关系
You don't have to go to school today. It's okay.
为什么?  下雪了吗?
Why? Is it snowing?
你有没有黑色礼服?
Do you have a black suit?
我又睡过头了
I overslept again, huh?
我们要到城里去参加一个重要会议
We have a very important meeting in the city.
吃了它  快点  快点
Eat that. Come on, come on, eat.
夫人  开门
Ma'am, open up. Just open up please.
- 很重要  - 什么?
- It's important. - What?
还有半个小时才开门
We don't open for half an hour!
请把门打开  很重要的事
Open the door, please. Just open the door. It's important.
对不起  我们还得过半小时开门
I-I'm sorry, we don't open for half an hour.
你叫什么名字  夫人?
What's your name, ma'am?
达茜
Darcy.
达茜  是个好听的名字
Darcy. That's a pretty name.
我有点困难  我需要给我的孩子租套衣服
I'm in a bit of a fix. I need a suit for my kid.
这是我儿子弗兰克
This is my son Frank.
- 他需要一套黑礼服  - 黑礼服
- He needs a black suit. - Black suit...
我家里有人死了
There was a death in the family.
我的父亲  85岁  战争英雄
My father, 85 years old, war hero.
是吗?
Yeah?
下午要举行葬礼  军式葬礼...
There's a funeral this afternoon, military funeral
飞机头上飞  21响礼炮
planes flying overhead, 21-gun salute.
弗兰克需要租套衣服用几个小时
Frank needs to borrow a suit for a couple of hours.
对不起  我们不出租衣服  也还没开门
I'm sorry, we don't loan suits, and we're not open.
达茜  求你  帮帮忙
Darcy... Darcy, please. Come back.
达茜  这是你的吗?
Darcy... is this yours?
我刚才在停车场发现的
I just found it in the parking lot.
一定是从你的脖子上滑落的
It must've slipped right off your neck.
别撞到路牙
Don't hit the curb.
现在下车  从后边绕过来给我开门
Now get out, walk around the back and hold the door open for me.
好的
All right.
- 然后呢?  - 好  不要咧嘴笑
- What's next? - Okay, stop grinning.
我进去后  你回到车前座等我
When I get inside, you go back to the front seat and wait.
即使警察来开罚单
Even if a cop comes and writes you a ticket
也不要挪动车  明白吗?
you don't move the car, understood?
爸  这都是为什么?
Dad, wha-what's all this for?
你知道为什么杨基队总是赢吗?
You know why the Yankees always win, Frank?
因为他们有米基·曼托?
'Cause they have Mickey Mantle?
不  是因为其它队总盯着他们的条纹衣服看
No, it's 'cause the other teams can't stop staring at those damn pinstripes.
瞧好了
Watch this.
美国大通银行的经理
The manager of Chase Manhattan Bank
要给你父亲开门了
is about to open the door for your father.
阿巴戈内尔先生...
Mr. Abagnale, um
我们通常不会贷款给那些有税务问题的人
we don't usually loan money to people who have unresolved business with the IRs.
那是个误会
That's a misunderstanding.
我用错了记账的人
I hired the wrong guy to do my books.
是个任何人都可能犯的错误
A mistake, I... anybody could make it.
我只需要你们帮助我渡过难关
I just need you guys to help me weather the storm.
先生  你正因骗税问题被政府调查
sir, you're being investigated by the government for tax fraud.
我的商店在新罗谢尔很有名
My store is a landmark in New Rochelle.
我的客户遍布纽约
I have customers all over New York.
但你不是大通银行的客户
Well, you're not a customer at Chase Manhattan.
我们不认识你
We don't know you.
我确信新罗谢尔的银行认识你
I'm sure your bank in New Rochelle, they know you,
- 能帮你摆脱困境  - 我的银行倒闭了
- they could help you out. - My bank went out of business.
像你们这样的银行使它们倒闭的
Banks like this one put them out of business.
我知道我犯了个错误  我承认这点
Now, I know I made a mistake, I admit that
但这些人想吸血
but these people want blood.
他们想要我的商店
They want my store.
甚至威胁过我说要把我投入监狱
They've threatened to put me in jail.
这是美国  对吗?  我不是罪犯
This is America, right? I'm not a criminal.
我是新罗谢尔旋转俱乐部终身会员
I'm a Medal of Honor winner a lifetime member
荣誉奖章获得者
of the New Rochelle Rotary Club.
我想求你做的就是帮我打败这些家伙
All I'm asking is for you to help me beat these guys.
这不是输赢问题  而是风险问题
It's not a question of winning and losing. It's a question of risk.
你们是世界上最大的银行
You're the largest bank in the world.
哪来...
Where's the fu...
哪里... 哪里有风险?
Whe... Where's the risk?
爸  你怎么能让他们像那样拿走我们的车?
Dad, how could you just let him take our car like that?
他多付了500美元  所以是我们拿了他的
He didn't take anything. We took him. He overpaid by $500.
得了  弗兰克
Come on, Frank.
我们去还衣服吧
Let's return the suit.
那地方不错
This place is good.
是小了些  但不用操那么多心
It's small but, you know it's going to be a lot less work.
家务活少多了
A lot less work for you.
老爸
Hey, Dad.
你母亲呢?
Where's your mother?
我不知道
I don't know.
她说什么要去找工作
she said something about going to look for a job.
她能做什么
What's she gonna be
在蜈蚣农场卖鞋?
a shoe salesman at a centipede farm?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
你想要点薄饼吗?
You want some pancakes?
在我儿子16岁生日这天  晚餐吃博饼?
For dinner? On my son's 16th birthday?
我们才不吃薄饼
We're not gonna eat pancakes.
你为什么那样看着我?  你以为我忘了?
Come on, why are you looking at me like that? You thought I forgot?
- 我没以为你忘了  - 我以你的名义
-I didn't think you forgot. -I opened a checking account
开了个支票账户
in your name.
账户里存了25美元  随便你买什么
I put $25 in the account so you can buy whatever you want.
- 别告诉你母亲  - 我不会的
- Don't tell your mother. - I won't.
多谢你  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
那家银行不是拒绝给你贷款了吗?
Didn't that bank turn you down for a loan, though?
是的  他们都拒绝我了
Yes, they all turned me down.
那怎么还在那儿开户?
Then why you opening a banking account with them?
因为迟早你会用到银行
Well, because one day, you'll want something from these people
贷款买房子  买车
a house, a car.
他们控制这些钱
They have all the money.
这有50张支票  弗兰克...
There's 50 checks there, Frank
也就是说  从今天开始...
which means, from this day on...
你就加入了他们的小俱乐部
you're in their little club.
我加入了他们的小俱乐部
I'm in their little club.
有了支票  就有了一切
You got that, you got it all.
上边甚至有我的名字
It's even got my name there, huh?
一步登天
To the moon.
- 一步登天  - 一步登天
-To the moon! -To the moon.
看见了吗?  那只不过是所学校
see that? It's just a school.
和西波恩中学没什么两样
No different than Westbourne.
妈  你说过要戒烟的
Ma... you said you were going to quit.
弗兰克   在这儿你不用穿校服
Frankie, you don't have to wear the uniform here.
为什么不脱了你的上衣呢?
Why don't you take off your jacket?
我习惯了
I'm used to it.
对不起
Excuse me.
什么事?
Oh, yes?
你知道上法语课的17号教室在哪?
Do you know where room 17 French is?
知道  在...
Yeah, it's...
但是你竟杀了他
But you frickin' killed him.
你在卖百科全书吗?
You selling encyclopedias?
他看上去像位代课老师
Yeah, he looks like a substitute teacher.
安静  各位!
Quiet down, people!
我叫阿巴戈内尔先生!
My name is Mr. Abagnale!
是阿巴戈内尔  不是阿巴戈诺勒...
That's Abagnale, not Abagnahlee
也不是阿巴戈内勒  而是阿巴戈内尔
not Abagnaylee, but Abagnale!
现在  请哪位来告诉我上次讲到哪里了
Now, somebody please tell me where you left off in your textbooks.
对不起  如果我需要再说一遍的话
Excuse me, people, if I need to ask again
我就要告你们全班的状
I'm going to write up the entire class.
坐下!
Take your seats!
第7章
Chapter seven.
请打开书到第8章...
Will you please open your textbooks to, uh, chapter eight
我们开始吧
and we'll get started?
对不起  你叫什么?
Excuse me, what's your name?
布拉德
Brad.
布拉德  你为什么不站到教室前面
Brad, why don't you get up here in front of the class here
朗读第5段对话
and read conversation number five?
法国
"Les Francais sonts
呃  一般
uh, generalement
在他们的国家
dans leur pais que...
几乎每个人都有这样的感觉
presque tout le monde a cette impression..."
他们派我来的
They sent for me.
他们说他们需要给罗伯塔找个代课老师
They said they needed a sub for Roberta.
我老远从狄克逊赶来
I came all the way from-from Dixon.
我总是给罗伯塔代课
Well, uh, I always sub for Roberta.
你为什么不读了?
Excuse me, why aren't you reading?
我再也不来贝拉明杰斐逊中学代课了!
I'll never come back to-to Bellarmine Jefferson again!
你告诉他们别给我打电话
You tell them not to call me!
他们认为像我这样一把年纪的妇女...
What do they think, it's easy for a woman my age
还花了我那么多路费容易吗?
and all the money that it costs to travel?
他们不会给我报销的
I tell you, they don't give a damn.
阿巴内尔先生和夫人
Mr. And Mrs. Abagnale
这个问题不是关于你儿子出勤率的
this is not a question of your son's attendance.
我很抱歉的告诉你们  在过去的一周中
I regret to inform you that for the past week
弗兰克替格拉瑟夫人教授了法语课
Frank has been teaching Mrs. Glasser's French class.
他干什么了?
He what?
你们的儿子假装成代课老师
Your son has been pretending to be a substitute teacher
给学生们讲课  布置作业...
lecturing the students, uh, giving out homework.
格拉瑟太太病了
Mrs. Glasser has been ill...
而代课老师又无法上课
and there was some confusion with the real sub.
昨天你们的儿子开了个家长会...
Your son held a teacher-parent conference yesterday
准备安排到特伦顿的一家法国面包厂实习
and was planning a class field trip to a French bread factory in Trenton.
你们明白了问题所在吗?
Do you see the problem we have?
- 达文波特小姐?  - 是的
- Mrs. Davenport? - Yeah.
我有个假条  不能上第5-6节课
Uh, I have a note to miss fifth and sixth period today.
- 跟医生有个约会  - 稍等一下
- Doctor's appointment. - One moment.
我马上回来
I'll be right with you.
- 什么?  - 你应该把它折起来
- Yes? - You should fold it.
你说什么?
What?
那个假条  是假的  对吗?
That note. It's a fake, right?
你应该折起来
You should fold it.
是我妈妈写的假条  我跟医生有预约
It's... It's a note from my mom. I have a doctor's appointment.
对  但纸没有折痕
Yeah, but there's no crease in the paper.
你妈妈递给你假条时...
When your mom hands you a note to miss school
一般是先折起来  再放进口袋里
the first thing you do is, you fold it and you put it in your pocket.
如果是真的  折痕在哪里?
I mean, if it's real, where's the crease?
弗兰克
Frankie.
妈  我回来了
Ma, I'm home.
还记得我和你说过的?
Oh, you remember that girl Joanna
那个女孩乔安娜吗?
I was telling you about?
今天我跟她约会了
I asked her out today.
我想我们要去参加3年级舞会
Think we're going to go to the Junior Prom.
妈  这是我的驾驶执照吗?
Ma, is this my driver's license?
只有这些  2间卧室
That's all there is, two bedrooms.
弗兰克
Oh, Frankie.
你还记得爸爸的朋友吗?
You remember Dad's friend?
杰克·巴恩斯
Jack Barnes?
俱乐部的
From the club.
- 你好  - 他路过这里来看看你父亲
- Hello. - He came by looking for your father.
我带他看了房子
I was giving him a tour of the apartment.
很宽敞  保拉
It's very, uh, uh, spacious, Paula.
爸爸在商店
Dad's at the store.
弗兰克  你长得越来越像你父亲了
so, Frank... you're getting to look more like your old man every day.
谢谢你的三明治  保拉
Thanks for the sandwich, Paula.
- 再见  - 等一下
- I'll see you later, eh? - Wait.
这是你的吗?
Is this yours?
谢谢  弗兰克
Well, thanks, Frank.
这是主席别针
Uh, that's the President's pin.
我要是丢了它  麻烦可就大了
I'd be in deep trouble if I lost that.
再见
I'll see you all later, eh?
你饿吗  弗兰克?
Are you hungry, Frankie?
我给你做三明治
I'll make you a sandwich.
杰克想跟你父亲谈生意
Jack wanted to talk business with your father.
他觉得我们应该找个律师控告政府
He thinks we should get a lawyer and sue the government.
他们对我们做的不合法
That is not legal what they're doing to us.
你怎么不说话?
Why aren't you saying anything?
你不会告诉他的  是吗?
You're not going to tell him... are you?
不会
No.
那就对了
That's right.
没有什么可说的
There's nothing to tell.
我要出去几个小时
I'm going out for a few hours
拜访一些网球俱乐部的朋友
to visit some old friends from the tennis club and...
我回家后  我们一起吃晚饭
when I get home, we'll all have dinner together.
好吗?
Right?
你什么也不会说
But you won't say anything
因为那样太傻...   对吗?
because it's... it's just silly, isn't it?
我们怎么控告政府?
How could we sue anybody?
你需要点钱吗  弗兰克?
Oh... do you need some money, Frankie?
拿几美元去买些唱片?
A few dollars to buy some record albums?
给你5块钱
Here, take five dollars.
或者10块
Or-Or ten.
你答应过要戒掉的
You promised you were going to quit.
妈  我回来了
Ma, I'm home!
你离我远点  听见了吗?
You... You stay away from me, hear me?
你离我远点  我不知道你是谁
You stay away from me... I don't know who you are
但如果你回来...
but if you ever come back here again...
弗兰克  冷静点  好吗?
Frankie! Frank, Frank, calm down, will you?
我叫迪克·科斯纳
I'm Dick Kesner.
我想让你把东西放这
Now, I want you to leave your things here
跟我进另一间屋
and follow me into the next room, okay?
他们都在等你
They're all waiting for you.
你不必害怕
You don't have to be scared.
我就在这里  弗兰克  我一直在这里
I'm right here, Frank. I'll always be here.
但是有法律
But there are laws.
这个国家的每一件事 都要合法
Everything in this country has to be legal.
所以我们要做些决定
so what we need to do is make some decisions.
科斯纳先生就是为这个来的
That's what Mr. Kesner is here for.
很多时候这些决定是由法庭来做的
Many times these decisions are left up to the courts
但可能会很贵  弗兰克
but that can be very expensive, Frank
- 人们为了孩子而打架  - 没人在打架
- people fighting over their children. - Nobody is fighting.
看着我  弗兰克  没人在打架
Look at me, Frank. Nobody is fighting.
爸  到底怎么了?
Dad, what's going on?
还记得你的祖母夏娃吗?
Do you remember your grandma, Eve?
她今天早晨到的
she arrived this morning.
你好
Hello.
你明白我们在跟你讲什么吗  弗兰克?
Do you understand what we're saying to you, Frank?
我和你父亲要离婚了
Your father and I are getting a divorce.
什么都不会改变
Nothing's gonna change.
我们还可以见面
We're still gonna see each other.
别说了  求你  不要打断
stop it, please, Frank. Don't interrupt.
你不必读完这些
Frank, you don't have to read all of this.
多数都是关于你父母的  成年人间烦人的事情
Most of it's for your parents... boring adult business...
但这段很重要...
but this paragraph right here, this is important
因为它说的是离婚后你将跟谁在一起...
because it states who you're gonna live with...
离婚后
after the divorce...
你受谁的监护
whose custody you will be in.
这里有个空白处
And there's a blank space right here.
你到厨房去  坐在桌前...
And I want you to go into the kitchen sit at the table
写上父亲或母亲的名字
and put a name down.
不要着急
You can take as long as you want
但是当你回到这个房间时...
but when you come back into this room...
我想看见那条线上写好了名字
I want to see a name on that line.
弗兰克  你只要写下个人名就行了
Frank, just write down a name and this will all be over.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
爸  什么名字?
Dad, what name?
你母亲或你父亲
Your mother or your father.
把名字写在那里 就那么简单
Just put the name there. It's as simple as that.
不要害怕
And don't look so scared.
这不是考试
It's not a test.
不回答错
There's no wrong answer.
请给1张到大中心的票
One ticket to Grand Central, please.
3.50美元  先生
That'll be $3.50, sir.
我付支票可以吗?
Is it okay if I write you a check?
卡尔   我何时可以给父亲打电话?
Carl, when do I get to call my father?
到纽约后你就可以打给他
You can call him when we get to New York.
1969年  法国  巴黎
我们7个小时后到飞机场
We leave for the airport in seven hours.
别动  一直坐在那里
Until then, just sit there.
安静点
Be quiet.
卡尔  旅馆的另外一侧有
You know, Carl, on the other side of the hotel
面对公园的套房
they got suites that face the park.
这是联邦调查局能担负的最好的房间了
It's the best room the FBI can afford.
没关系  我原来呆的地方更差
It's okay, I've stayed in worse.
马德里克先生...
Mr. Mudrick...
马德里克先生  求你  你得听我说
Mr. Mudrick, please. You have to listen.
我不想听你解释
I don't want to hear your story.
2张支票退回来了
This is two checks that bounced.
你知道我有多大的麻烦吗?
You know how much trouble I'm in?
不  听我说  我告诉你  是银行  银行犯了一个错误
No, but listen, I'm telling you, the bank, they made the mistake.
我马上再给你写张支票!
I'll write you another check right now!
我看上去像小孩子那么好骗吗?
What, do I look like I was born yesterday?
你看  现在是半夜
Look, it's midnight, Mr. Mudrick.
- 我能去哪?  - 你是个孩子  回家去
- Where am I gonna go? - You're a goddamn kid. Go home.
我希望你明白
I mean, I hope you understand.
我的老板派我到 布鲁克林区  然后到皇后区
My boss sent me to Brooklyn, then Queens.
现在他想让我去长岛...
Now he wants me in Long Island
带些顾客来城里玩一晚上
to take a few clients out for a night on the town.
对不起  我不能兑现其它银行的支票
I'm sorry, but we're not allowed to cash checks from other banks.
没法确认它们有效
How would we know if they were any good?
你说你叫什么名字来着?
What did you say your name was?
- 阿什蕾  - 阿什蕾
- Ashley. - Ashley.
你知道我在外边人行道上发现了什么
you know what I found on the sidewalk out there?
一定是从你脖子上滑落的
Must've slipped right off your neck.
有什么需要我帮助吗  年轻人?
Is there something I can help you with, son?
下星期是我祖母的生日
Well, you see, it's my grandmother's birthday next week
我想送给她件什么特别的东西
and I want to get her something extra-special.
求你了 我下星期考试  而书却丢了
Please, I mean it's my midterm next week and my books were stolen.
求你了  只是5美元
Please, it's just five dollars.
没人会知道的
No one would have to know.
对不起  但我们不允许
I'm sorry, but we are not allowed
收不认识的人的支票
to take checks from people we don't know.
欢迎来到纽约  很高兴你回来了  机长
Pleasure to have you back, Captain Carlson.
怎么样  安吉洛?
What do you think, Angelo?
番茄今天下午熟了
The tomatoes are ripe this afternoon.
这是什么?
Well, what have we here?
- 能签个名吗? -肯定行
- Can I have your autograph? - ou betcha.
- 也能给我签名吗?  - 你将来当飞行员?
- Can I have your autograph, too? - You gonna be a pilot?
好  签一个
All right, then.
给你  在学校努力学啊.
There you go. Work hard in school.
亲爱的爸爸
Dear Dad:
我已经决定去当飞行员
I have decided to become an airline pilot.
我已经申请了所有的大航空公司
I have applied to all the big airlines
有希望的面试已经排满日程了
and I have several promising interviews lined up.
妈妈怎样?
How's Mom?
你最近给她打电话了吗?
Have you called her lately?
爱你的  儿子  弗兰克
Love, your son, Frank.
你好
Hello.
我是穆偌中学的弗兰克·布莱克
I'm Frank Black from Murrow High school
我跟摩根先生有个约会
and I have an appointment with Mr. Morgan.
你就是给学校的报纸写文章的年轻人
You're the young man who's writing the article for the school paper.
对  是我  我想知道
Yes, ma'am, that's me. I want to know
关于成为飞行员的每一件事
everything there is to know about being a pilot.
泛美公司都飞哪些飞机场?
What airports does Pan Am fly to?
飞行员1年收入多少?
What does a pilot make in a year?
谁告诉他们往哪儿飞?
And who tells them where they're gonna fly to?
慢点  一个一个来
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down. Just take 'em one at a time.
好的  这是什么意思...
All right. What does it mean
当一个飞行员问另一个飞行员:
when one pilot says to another pilot:
"你装配了些什么?"
"What kind of equipment are you on?"
他们想知道你们使用什么样的飞机
They just want to know what kind of aircraft you're flying:
是DC-8还是707  或者星座式
Is it a DC-8 707, Constellation?
还有那些我见过的飞行员戴的徽章是干什么的?
And what about those I.D. badges that I've seen pilots wear?
每个飞行员有两样东西必须
Well, every pilot has to have two things with him
随身携带  一个是航空公司的职员徽章
at all times: One is his airline personnel badge...
就像泛美航空公司的这个
Looks just like this one here, from Pan Am...
另一个就是联邦航空局的执照
the other one is their FAA license...
就像这个一样
and that looks just like this.
先生  我能复印1份这
Oh. Sir, do you think I can make a copy of this
贴在我的文章里吗?
to put into my article?
弗兰克  你拿去吧  再有3年过期了
Oh, Frank, you can have that one. It's three years expired.
谢谢  还有你的身份徽章呢?
Aw, thanks! And what about your I.D. badge?
你还有没有一个多余的借给我?
You have an extra one I could borrow?
那个我帮不了你
Oh, no, I can't help you there.
要从宝丽来公司定制
Those are special-ordered from Polaroid.
唯一弄到它的办法
The only way to get one of those
就是成为一名真的泛美公司的飞行员
is to become a real live pilot for Pan American Airways.
泛美航空
这是泛美公司  要我帮忙吗?
Pan Am, may I help you?
是的  你好  我打电话是为了一套制服
Yeah, hello. I'm calling about a uniform.
- 等我转到采购部  - 谢谢
- Hold for Purchasing. - Thank you.
采购部
Purchasing.
我是一名来自旧金山基地的副驾驶员
Hi. I'm a copilot based out of san Francisco.
我昨晚飞到纽约
I flew a flight into New York last night
但问题是  我三小时后要去巴黎  马上要出发
but the problem is... I'm headed out to, uh, Paris in three hours.
你需要什么帮忙?
How can we help you?
我把我的制服送到酒店清洗
I sent my uniform to be cleaned through the hotel
但我想他们给弄丢了
and I... I guess they must have lost it.
他们丢了制服  这事经常发生
They lost a uniform. Happens all the time.
去百老汇街19号  好工制服公司
Go down to the Well-Built Uniform Company at Ninth and Broadway.
他们是我们的制服提供商
They're our uniform supplier.
我会告诉罗森先生你要去
I'll tell Mr. Rosen you're coming.
你看上去当飞行员太年轻了
You look too young to be a pilot.
我是副驾驶员
I'm a copilot.
为什么这么紧张?
Why so nervous?
你会有何感觉  如果你...
How would you feel if you, uh
第一周刚上班就把制服丢了?
Lost your uniform first week on the job?
放松点
Relax.
泛美公司有的是制服
Pan Am's got lots of uniforms.
一共是164美元
It's gonna be $164.
很好  我给你写张支票
Great. I'II, uh, I'll write you a check.
对不起  不收支票  不收现金
sorry, no checks, no cash.
你得写下你的职员身份号码
You'll have to fill in your employee I.D. number
我向泛美公司收帐
and then I'll bill Pan Am.
然后他们再从你下次薪水中扣除
They'll take it out of your next paycheck.
那更好
Even better.
亲爱的爸爸...
Dear Dad:
你总是告诉我一个诚实的人  没什么可怕的
You always told me that an honest man has nothing to fear.
所以我尽量不去害怕
So I'm trying my best not to be afraid.
对不起我离家出走了  但你不用担心
I'm sorry I ran away, but you don't have to worry.
我现在要把那些都找回来  爸爸
I'm gonna get it all back now, Daddy.
我保证  我要都找回来
I promise. I'm going to get it all back.
你是真的飞行员吗?
Are you a real live pilot?
我肯定是  小姐  你叫什么名字?
I sure am, little lady. What's your name?
- 席琳  - 席琳  很高兴见到你
- Celine. - Celine, it's a pleasure to meet you.
我也很高兴见到你
It's a pleasure to meet you, too.
50  70
That's fifty, seventy
80  90  100美元
eighty, ninety, one hundred dollars.
祝你在巴黎过得愉快
You have yourself a great time in Paris.
我总是过得愉快
I always do.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我叫约翰.摩迪治  我管理这家分行
I'm John Modiger. I manage this branch.
感谢你来到这里  使用我们的银行服务
I want to thank you for coming in and using our institution.
幸会  约翰
Well, it's a pleasure to meet you, John.
- 我还会来的  - 好
- I'll be back again. - Good.
你以前住过我们酒店吗?
Have you stayed with us before?
不  我以前主要是在西海岸一带
Uh, no, I've been primarily based on the West Coast.
我可以给你写张支票付房钱吗?
Is it all right if I write you a check for the room?
- 没问题  先生  - 很好
- No problem, sir. - Great.
我想知道  能否使用个人支票?
I was also wondering if I could write you a personal check?
对于航空公司的职员 我们最多兑现100美元个人支票
For airline personnel, we cash personal checks up to $100.
薪水支票我们最多兑现300美元现金
Payroll checks we cash up to $300.
你是说工资支票给兑现300美元?
Did you say $300 for a payroll check?
亲爱的爸爸...
Dear Dad:
我已经决定要成为泛美航空公司的飞行员了
I've decided to become a pilot for Pan American Airways...
泛美是天空中最值得信任的名字
the most trusted name in the skies.
他们已经接受我参加他们的培训
They've accepted me into their training program
并说如果我努力工作
and told me that if I work hard
不久我就真要插上翅膀了
I should earn my wings real soon.
请跟10年级的乔安娜·卡尔顿联系
Please get in touch with Joanna Carlton from the tenth grade.
告诉他说我抱歉不能带她去3年级舞会
Tell her I'm sorry that I could not take her to the Junior Prom.
爱你的  儿子  弗兰克
Love, your son, Frank.
- 你好吗?  - 很好  谢谢
- Hello, how are you? - Fine, thank you.
我有1张薪水支票想兑现金
I have a payroll check here I'd like to cash.
没问题
Certainly.
对不起
Uh, excuse me.
我肯定你经常听人这么说
I'm sure you hear this all the time but,
但你的眼睛是我见过的最美丽的一双
you have the most beautiful eyes I have ever seen.
是  我经常听人这么说
Yeah, I do get that all the time.
你想兑现什么面额的钞票?
How would you like it?
对不起  先生
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
我们要等银行一小时后开门才有现金
We won't have any cash until the banks open in an hour
但我肯定
but, uh, I'm sure
他们可以在飞机场给你兑现支票
they can cash your check at the airport.
飞机场?
The airport?
谁在飞机场兑现支票?
Who cashes checks at the airport?
航空公司
Well, the airlines, sir.
他们总是给自己兑现
They've always taken care of their own.
- 你好  - 请问是要搭机吗?
- Hello. - Hi. Are you deadheading?
什么?
What?
你要搭机去迈阿密吗?
Are you my deadhead to Miami?
是的
Yes, yes.
是  我要搭机  给你
Yeah, I'm the deadhead. Here you go.
你有点晚了  但驾驶舱备用椅空着
You're a little late, but the jump seat is open.
我干这一行已经有段时间了
You know it's been awhile since I've done this.
但备用椅在哪?
Which one's the jump seat again?
旅途愉快
Have a nice flight.
你要搭我的飞机吗?
Are you my deadhead?
弗兰克  奥利弗机长
Frank, Captain Oliver.
- 约翰·拉金  副驾驶  - 你好
-John Larkin, the copilot. -Hello.
福瑞德·塔利  飞机工程师
Fred Tulley, flight engineer.
弗兰克.泰勒  泛美公司
Frank Taylor, Pan Am.
谢谢捎我一程  小伙子们
Thanks for giving me a lift, boys.
坐下吧  弗兰克  我们要起飞了
Go ahead and take a seat, Frank. We're about to push.
你开什么飞机  DC-8?
What kind of equipment you on, DC-8?
是707
Uh, 707.
你刚到就返回去?
You turning around on the redeye?
我下几个月要在洲际之间来回飞
Uh, I'm jumping puddles for the next few months
通过给那些又病又累的人替班  来多挣点钱
trying to earn my keep running leapfrogs for the weak and weary.
没什么不好意思  我们都是这么过来的
No shame in that. We all did it.
- 坐吧  - 谢谢
- Have a seat. - Thank you.
起飞后你想喝点什么吗?
Would you like a drink after takeoff?
牛奶?
M-Milk?
- 速度: 80节 (时速150公里)  - 确认
- 80 knots. - Check.
- 到达仰转速度  - 仰转
- V-one. - Rotate.
- 到达爬升速度  - 正仰角
- V-two. - Positive rate.
收起落架
Gear up.
亲爱的爸爸:
Dear Dad:
今天我毕业
Today was graduation.
我现在是副驾驶
I am now a copilot
每月挣1400美元  外加福利
earning $1,400 a month plus benefits
而最好的一点是
and the best part is
他们告诉我说我的家里人可以免费飞
they tell me my family can fly for free.
所以告诉妈妈去准备行李  买套新的泳衣
So tell Mom to pack her bags and buy a new swimsuit
因为我要带你们去夏威夷过圣诞节
because I'm taking us all to Hawaii for Christmas.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
再见  弗兰克
Aloha, Frank.
- 你好  免费乘客  - 你好
- Hello, deadhead. - Hello.
旅途愉快吗?
Enjoying your free ride?
玛茜...
Marci...
这个是你掉的吗
did you drop this?
- 一定是从你脖子上滑落下来的  - 不是
- Must've slipped right off your neck. - No...
不是我的!
No!
不...
No...
为什么停下来?
Why are you stopping?
我想告诉你件事  玛茜
I want to tell you something, Marci.
这是到目前...
This is by far...
我曾经有过的最好的约会
the best date I have ever been on.
请帮我开一个货币市场账户
I'd like to open a Money Market, please.
好的
Okay.
欢迎来迈阿密互助银行  能为您做点什么?
Welcome to Miami Mutual Bank. How may I help you?
我叫弗兰克·泰勒  是泛美航空公司的副驾驶
My name is Frank Taylor. I'm a copilot for Pan Am.
我想办理支票兑现
I'd like to cash this check here, and then
然后带你去吃牛排晚餐
I'd like to take you out for a steak dinner.
然后我们把支票放进磁性墨迹识别机里
And then we feed the checks into the MICR machine
它用一种特殊的墨水
which uses special ink
在支票的底部给支票加编码
to encode the account numbers on the bottom of the checks.
那些编码在哪里?
And where are these numbers?
就在这儿
They're, um... right here.
- 在这儿?  - 看到了吗?
- Right there? - see?
它们叫做路由编码
They're called routing numbers.
那么这些支票要路由到哪里去呢?
so where do the checks get routed to?
我不知道  从来没有人问过我
You know, I don't exactly know. Nobody ever asked me that before.
我们下一个竞标的物品还是
Our next item up for bid is also...
来自新泽西中心银行的抵押没收品
from the Jersey Central Bank foreclosure.
这是台磁性墨迹识别机  用来给银行支票编码的
This is a MICR encoder a machine used to encode bank checks.
有起标价吗?
Do I have an opening bid?
我们的罪犯是个从东海岸开始的伪造支票者
Our unknown subject is a paperhanger who started working on the East Coast.
在过去的几个星期里  他发明了一种
In the last few weeks, this unsub has developed
新型的支票欺诈手法  我称它"飘"
a new form of check fraud which I'm calling "the float."
他的做法就是
What he's doing is
在不同的银行开支票帐户...
he's opening checking accounts at various banks
然后涂改那些在支票
then changing the MICR ink routing numbers
底部的编码
at the bottom of those checks.
请播放下一张
Next slide, please.
下一张
遥控器坏了
Uh, the remote thing is broken.
你得手动
You'll have to do it by hand.
华盛顿特区  FBI总部
你必须...  试...
You've gotta... try the...
马伦探员  它因该...
Agent Mullen, it should be...
应该是侧面的那个方按钮
it should be the square button just there by the side.
转盘不好使
This carousel doesn't work.
是个坏转盘
It's a bad carousel you got there.
- 谢谢  马伦探员  - 只能用手动
- Thank you, Agent Mullen. - Got to move it manually.
这是美联储的12个银行分布图
This is a map of the 12 banks of the U.s. Federal Reserve.
下一张
slide.
每个银行的识别机的扫描仪
MICR scanners at every bank
读取支票底部的这些数字  下一张
read these numbers at the bottom of a check... slide...
然后把支票发送到相关的银行兑现
and then, ship that check off to its corresponding branch.
卡尔  对我们这些不熟悉银行诈骗的
Carl, for those of us who are unfamiliar with bank fraud
你能不能告诉我们  你在讲什么?
you mind telling us what the hell you're talking about?
东海岸分行的编号是从01到06
The East Coast branches are numbered zero-one to zero-six.
中部地区分行的编号是07到08
The central branch is zero-seven, zero-eight
如此类推
so on, so forth.
底部的那些号码
You mean those numbers on the bottom of a check
有什么实际意思吗?
actually mean something?
所有这些都是我两天前做的报告
All of this was in the report I filed two days ago.
如果你把02改成12  这就意味着...
If you change... a zero-two to a one-two
这就意味着在纽约提现金的支票
that means that check, which was cashed in New York
不会再转到纽约联邦分行了
is not go to the New York Federal Branch
而是会被转到... 都回到旧金山分行
but it is rerouted all the way to the san Francisco Federal Branch.
银行在两个星期里  不会知道支票已被退回了
The bank doesn't even know the check has bounced for two weeks
这就意味着我们的犯人会待在一个地方
which means our unsub can stay in one place
在同一个城市不断重施故技
paper the same city over and over again
直至支票送经全国
while his checks circle the country.
你应该和我的太太谈谈
You know, you want to talk to my wife.
我们家她管支票本
she's the one balances the checkbook at our house.
下一张
Next slide.
爸爸!
Daddy!
我的孩子  飞行员
My son, the birdman.
穿制服了
some uniform, Frank.
你觉得怎么样?
What do you think?
很好
Nice.
坐吧
sit down.
爸爸  你收到明信片了吗?
so, Dad... Daddy, have you gotten the postcards?
当然
Of course.
这叉子冰凉
This fork is ice cold.
不  爸爸  那是冰镇的吃沙拉用的叉子
No, no, Dad, th-that's a chilled salad fork.
这是个高档餐厅  你知道
It's a fancy restaurant, you know.
这儿
Well, here...
- 我有东西送你  - 什么东西?
- I-I got you something. - What's that?
打开看看
Open it.
你知道那些是什么  对吧?
You know what those are, right?
那是一辆1965年卡迪拉克敞篷车的钥匙
Those are the keys to a 1965 Cadillac DeVille convertible.
全新的  爸爸
Brand-new, Dad.
车身红色  车内白色...
Red with white interior
分开的座位  空调  全套的配置
split seats, air conditioning, the works.
你送给我一辆卡迪拉克?
Are you giving me a Cadillac?
我送给你一辆卡迪拉克
Yeah. I'm giving you a Cadillac.
爸爸  它就停在楼下
Dad, sh-she's parked downstairs.
我们吃完午饭后
When we're done eating lunch
就开到妈妈那里去...
why don't you, you know, drive on over to Mom's house
带上她兜兜风
pick her up, take a little joyride?
如果税务局发现我开辆新的双门轿车到处跑
Do you know what would happen if the IRs found out
你知道会发生什么?
I was driving around in a new coupe?
我坐火车来的  弗兰克
I took the train here, Frank.
也要坐火车回去
I'm taking the train home.
好吧
All right.
我有很多钱
I have plenty of money.
你知道  需要什么尽管讲
You know, if you ever, ever need anything...
你担心我?
You worried?
担心我?
About me?
不  我不是担心
No, I'm not... I'm not worried.
你觉得我自己买不起车?
You think I can't buy my own car?
两只老鼠掉进奶油桶里  弗兰克
Two mice fell in a bucket of cream, Frank.
我是哪只?
Which one am I?
你是第二只老鼠
You're that second mouse.
我今天路过商店
I went by the store today.
我不得不把商店关几天
I had to close the store for awhile.
只是个时间问题  弗兰克
It's all about timing, Frank.
狗屁政府清楚这点
The goddamn government knows that.
他们落井下石
They hit you when you're down.
我不想让他们把商店夺走  所以我就...
I wasn't going to let them take it from me, so I just...
干脆自己关了店门  看他们能把我怎样
shut the doors myself, called their bluff.
早晚他们是要忘了我的
sooner or later, they'll forget about me.
我明白
I understand, I...
你告诉妈了吗?
Have you told Ma?
你母亲  她很固执
she's so stubborn, your mother.
不要担心  我不会不劝她就让她走的
Don't worry. I'm not going to let her go without a fight.
我要劝她为我们留下...
I been fighting for us...
老爸?
Dad?
从我们相遇的那天起
since the day we... we met.
爸爸  在那些人当中...
Daddy, out of all those men
是你赢得了妈妈的心  记得吗?
you were the one that took her home, remember that.
200人坐在那个小厅里看她跳舞
200 men, sitting in that tiny social hall watching her dance.
那个小镇叫什么名字来着?
What was the name of that town?
- 曼沙  爸爸  - 是的
- Montrichard, Dad. - Yeah.
我一句法语也不会说
I didn't speak a word of French
而六个星期后  她成了我的妻子
and six weeks later, she was my wi...
她还是你的妻子
she's your wife.
我儿子今天给我买了辆卡迪拉克
My son bought me a Cadillac today.
我想该为此干一杯
I think that calls for a toast.
为了天空中最好的飞行员
To the best damn pilot in the sky.
不像你想的那样
It's not what you think.
我只是名副驾驶
I'm just a copilot.
你看见这些人在注视你吗?
You see these people staring at you?
这些是纽约市最有权势的人
These are the most powerful people in New York City
他们总是越过肩膀偷看
and they keep peeking over their shoulders
想知道今晚你去哪里
wondering where you're going tonight.
你要去哪里  弗兰克?
Where you going, Frank?
爸爸  没有人在盯着我
Dad, nobody's staring at me.
什么奇异的地方吗?
some place exotic?
告诉我你要去哪里
Just tell me where you're going.
洛杉... 好莱坞
Los An... Hollywood.
好莱坞?
Hollywood.
我们其余的人...
The rest of us...
真是笨蛋
really are suckers.
所以我穿了这红衣服和高跟鞋  对吗?
so, I got on this red dress and these high heels, right?
我外边这儿戴了胸罩
And I got a bra, like, out here, okay?
我追两个波多黎各人
And I'm chasing these two Puerto Rican guys
加利福尼亚  好莱坞
在公园里
through the park.
他们拎一个装满了从银行抢来的钱的箱子
They got a suitcase filled with bank robbery loot.
我大喊: "联邦调查局  不许动! "
Okay, I'm screaming out, "FBI, freeze!"
我去拿枪  却发现不在胸罩里
And I'm reaching for my gun, but I can't find it in the bra.
它太他妈大了
It's so damn big
我想我会不会把乳头射掉
I thought I was going to shoot my tits off.
这是个有趣的故事
You know, that's a funny story.
别人总是被逗笑
People always laugh at that story.
让我问你一个问题  阿穆德斯基先生
Let me ask you a question, Mr. Amdursky.
如果你觉得当便衣很有意思
If you were having so much fun undercover
那你为什么转到银行诈骗科?
why did you transfer to bank fraud?
不是我要求转的
I didn't transfer.
我受责难被重分配的
I was censured and reassigned.
就像是受罚了 我就受罚了
It's like being punished. I was punished.
我出外勤时犯了个错误
I screwed up in the field.
你呢?  福克斯先生
What about you, Mr. Fox?
有没有在出外勤时  因为犯错而受罚过?
Were you... punished for screwing up in the field?
没有  我以前从没穿便衣去调查过
Oh, no, no, no, I've never worked in the field before.
我在司法部的文职申请部审计背景调查
I audited background investigations of Department of Justice clerical applicants.
真是太好了  我要一队便衣
Well, that's just great. I ask for a team
结果他们给我派了两个不称职的人
and they drag the bottom of the Pacific.
我能问你个问题吗?  汉拉蒂探员
You mind if I ask you a question, Agent Handratty?
你为什么总是那么严肃?
How come you're so serious all the time?
这干扰你了吗  阿穆德斯基先生?
Does it bother you, Mr. Amdursky?
对  是干扰我了
Yeah. Yeah, it does bother me.
干扰你了吗  福克斯先生?
Does it bother you, Mr. Fox?
我想有一点
A little, I guess.
你们想听我讲个笑话吗?
Well, would you like to hear me tell a joke?
想  我们很想听你讲个笑话
Yeah. Yeah, we'd love to hear a joke from you.
咚咚敲门
Knock, knock.
是谁?
Who's there?
去你妈的
Go fuck yourselves.
年轻可爱  高挑棕肤
Tall and tan and young and lovely
这来自Ipanema的女孩
The girl from Ipanema...
他兑换了三张支票  都取到钱了
He cashed three checks. They all cleared.
我今天打算存这张
I was going to deposit this one today.
我不想有麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
没有麻烦
No trouble.
一点也没有
No trouble at all.
我们就拿着这张支票上路了
We'll just take this check and be on our way.
- 谢谢  - 很好
- Thank you. - Good.
因为我不想让我的顾客受到干扰
Because I don't want my customers harassed.
你在说什么?  他仍然在这儿吗?
What are you saying, he's still here?
201房间
201.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 到转弯了  - 谢谢  儿子
- Corner here. - Oh, thanks, son.
- 有楼梯  - 楼梯
- some steps. - steps.
墨菲先生  你好吗?
Hey, Mr. Murphy, how are you?
- 是弗兰克吗?  - 是我
- Is that Frank? - Yeah, it's Frank.
- 弗兰克  你好吗?  - 您膝盖怎么样了?
- Hey, Frank, how are you? - How's the knee?
得了  我现在就跟你赛跑
Come on, I'll race you right now.
- 小心点  - 好的
- Take care. - Okay, Frank.
得了  卡尔  这个家伙是个文人
Come on, Carl, this guy's a pen and ink man.
这个该死的裱糊工  他连枪都没带
A goddamn paperhanger. He doesn't even carry a gun.
我们为什么不和你一起走  卡尔?
Why can't we go with you, Carl?
打起精神好好干  我会给你俩买冰激凌吃
You just keep your eyes open, do your job and I'll buy you both a Good Humor bar.
没事  夫人  联邦调查局
It's all right, ma'am. FBI.
201室
201... 201, 201.
联邦调查局!
FBI!
从卫生间出来!
Come out of the bathroom!
step out of the bathroom!
手放在头上
Hands on your head.
是新的IBM电动打字机
Oh, that's the new IBM selectric.
把手放到头上
Put your hands on your head.
五秒钟内就能改变打印格式
You can change the print type in five seconds.
- 闭嘴!  - 只是突出了个球.
-Shut up! -Just pop out the ball.
把手放到头上!
Put your hands on your head! Put your hands...!
他有200多张支票  1加仑印度墨水
You know, he's got over 200 checks here, a gallon
- 还有草图  - 举起手
- of India ink, drafting. - Hands on your head!
甚至发自泛美的薪水信封都写着
Even has little payroll envelopes addressed to himself
- 他自己的地址  - 放下!  扔掉!
- from Pan Am. - Put it down! Drop it!
放松点!
Relax.
你来晚了  我是巴里·艾伦
You're late, all right? My name's Allen, Barry Allen
美国特情局的
United states secret service.
你的嫌疑犯刚才想从窗户跳出去
Your boy just tried to jump out the window.
被我同伴拘捕了
My partner has him in custody downstairs.
你少鬼扯
I don't know what you're talking about.
你以为只有联邦调查局在追捕他吗?
You think the FBI are the only ones on this guy?
我的意思是说
I mean, come on.
别争了  他在这里还在伪造政府支票
Come on, he's dabbling in government checks here.
我们是根据这张才跟踪到他的
We've been following a paper trail on this guy
已经有好几个月了
for months now.
你介意把枪从我的脸上移开吗?
Hey, you mind taking that gun out of my face?
拜托了  真的  这让我感觉紧张
Please. Really. I mean, it makes me nervous.
- 让我看看你的证件  - 当然
- Let me see some credentials. - Yeah, sure.
把我的钱包都拿去吧
Take my whole wallet.
你还想要我的枪?  你来拿好了
You want my gun, too? Come over here. Take my gun.
帮个忙  看窗外  看
Hey, hey, look, just do me a favor. Take a look outside. Look.
看看窗外
Look out the window.
我的同伴正押着他走向那车  看
My partner's walking him to the car as we speak... Look.
在我进来时  老家伙差点尿裤子
Old guy almost pissed in his pants when I came through the door.
他直接从这窗户跳到我的车上
He jumped right through the window onto the hood of my car.
- 墨菲?  - 嗯?
- Hey, Murph? -Yeah?
给洛杉矶警察局打电话
Call the LAPD again.
我不想让人走进我的犯罪现场
I don't want people walking through my crime scene.
我没想到情报局卷了进来
I didn't expect the secret service on this.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
你叫什么名字?
Well, what's your name?
汉莱提  卡尔·汉莱提
Handratty, Carl Handratty.
我能看一下你的证件吗?
Mind if I see some identification?
- 当然  - 小心驶得万年船
- sure. - You never can be too careful these days.
运气不好  卡尔
Well, tough luck, Carl.
早来5分钟  你就能抓个正着
Five minutes earlier you would've landed yourself a pretty good collar.
没关系
It's all right.
要是晚来10秒钟  就被打死了
Ten seconds later, and you'd have been shot.
介意我跟你一起去吗?
Mind if I come downstairs with you?
- 我得看看这家伙  - 当然行
- I got to take a look at this guy. - Sure thing.
帮个忙  在这等我下
Just, uh, do me a favor and sit tight for a second
我下楼去取证据
while I get this evidence downstairs.
我不想让服务员进来铺床
You know, I don't want some maid walking through here and making the bed.
- 洛杉矶警察局的人随时会到  - 等等
- LAPD should be here any sec. - Wait.
你的钱包
Your wallet.
替我保管一会儿  我相信你
You hang onto it for a minute. I trust you.
情报局
secret service.
见鬼!
Oh, goddamn it!
真愚蠢
It was stupid.
我犯了个愚蠢的错误
I made a stupid mistake.
别想了
Forget about it.
还有百多宗没破的案件
There are hundreds of unknown subjects out there.
我能抓住这家伙
I-I can get this guy, sean.
造假的人所做的最糟糕的事  就是被人看见脸
The worst thing a paperhanger can do is show his face.
我看了报告
I read the report.
1米80高  棕色头发  27到30岁之间
six feet tall, brown hair, 27 to 30 years of age
70公斤
160 pounds.
这样的人到处都是
This could be almost anybody.
我听见了他的声音  看到了他的脸
I heard his voice, Sean, I saw his face.
他没有什么可掩藏的了
There's nothing for him to hide behind anymore.
小心些
Just be careful.
你干了12年了
You got 12 years in.
没有人干扰你的工作
Nobody bothers you down on the first floor.
你写了那本银行诈骗案的书
You practically wrote the book on bank fraud.
那会让你有一天成为部门主管的
That's the kind of thing that can make you section chief someday.
不要把自己放到那种位置上
Just don't put yourself in this type of position.
哪种位置?
What type of position?
受辱的位置
Position of being humiliated.
你想听我讲个笑话吗?
sean, would you like to hear me tell a joke?
说吧
Yeah, sure.
咚咚敲门
Knock, knock!
我的下个问题是  飞行员退休后...
so, my-my next question is, when a pilot retires
泛美每个月都给他们发张支票吗?
uh, Pan Am sends them a check every single month?
对  按养老金计划给他们发支票和福利
Uh, yeah, pension program sends a check and benefits.
支票上有多少钱?
How much is that check for?
我现在没有心情谈这个
Uh, kid, I'm really not in the mood for this right now.
那个空中强盗都快把我搞疯了
This skywayman's driving me crazy.
哪个强盗?
Who's the skywayman?
一个假扮成泛美飞行员  到处飞的疯子
Ah, some nut that's flying around the country posing as a Pan Am pilot.
今天报纸有他的一个栏目
There's a column about him in the paper today.
我不断告诉他们说这不是我的问题
I keep telling them this is not my problem.
这家伙甚至不飞泛美
This guy doesn't even fly Pan Am.
他飞别的公司
Flies everybody else.
他飞联合  环球  大陆  东部...
Flies United, TWA, Continental, Eastern...
空中强盗
The skywayman.
报界喜欢这小丑
Newspaper loves this clown.
他们称他为空中的詹姆斯·邦德
They call him "the James Bond of the sky."
- 你说...?  - 邦德  詹姆斯.邦德
- Did you say...? - Bond, James Bond.
告诉我  琼  他为什么那样做?
Tell me, Joan, why does he do it?
- 他喜欢赢  - 快点  快点
- He likes to win. - Come on, come on.
我们20分钟就会着陆.
We'll be landing in 20 minutes.
你想玩简单的还是玩难的?
Do you want to play it easy or the hard way?
这不是镇静剂.
And this isn't a tranquilizer.
好了  普茜  你对飞机的了解要比枪多得多
Well, Pussy, you do know a lot more about planes than guns.
你好  普茜
Hello, Pussy.
- 你肯定是这种西装?  - 肯定
- Now, you're sure this is the suit, right? - Positive.
跟他在电影里穿的完全一样
It's the exact suit he wore in the movie.
好  我买3套
Okay. I'll take three.
没问题  弗莱明先生
Certainly, Mr. Fleming.
现在你缺的就是一辆
Now what you need is one of those
他开的那种外国小跑车
little foreign sports cars that he drives.
你好
Hello.
我以前见过你吗?
Haven't I seen you before?
也许
Maybe.
几年以前我上过《17岁》 的封面
A couple years ago, I was on the cover of Seventeen.
你是那个模特  对吗?  谢丽尔
You're that model, right? Cheryl.
是
Yes.
我同学总喜欢把你的照片贴在存衣柜里
The guys used to put your picture on their lockers.
我看见的停在外面的那辆银色轿车  是你的吗?
Isn't that your silver car I saw parked out front?
对  其中一辆
Yeah. One of them.
所以  能给我签个名吗?
so, think I could get an autograph?
你房间里有笔吗?
Do you have a pen in your room?
像你这样的人可以买任何想要的东西
Man like you can buy anything he wants.
他在旅馆的礼品店里买了一副纸牌
He buys a deck of cards at the hotel gift shop.
你想看我耍扑克把戏吗?
Well, you want to see a card trick?
这扑克价值多少钱?
How much did these cards cost?
我想55分吧
Oh, 55 cents, I think.
如果楼下旅馆的礼品店里把我卖了
And if they sold me downstairs at the hotel gift shop...
你会付多少钱?
how much would you pay?
对...
I'm sor...
对不起  我给什么付多少钱?
I'm sorry, how mu... how much would I pay for what?
一整夜
The entire night.
我陪你一整晚你付我多少钱?
How much would you pay me for the entire night?
谢丽尔  我真不知道
Cheryl, I... I really don't know.
不要害怕
Don't be scared.
出个价
Make me an offer.
300美元?
$300?
抓牌
Go fish.
500美元?
Uh, 500 dollars?
抓牌
Go fish.
600美元?
$600.
抓牌!
Go fish.
1000美元
$1,000.
好
Okay.
1000美元
$1,000.
好
Okay.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
等等  你去哪儿?
Wait a second. Where are you going?
我下楼去兑现支票
I'm going downstairs to cash a check.
你想旅馆能给你兑现1000美元支票?
You think this hotel is going to cash a $1,000 check
凌晨3点?
at 3:00am?
是张纽约储蓄和贷款支票
It's a New York savings and Loan check.
像金子一样  他们会给兑现的
It's like gold. They'll cash it.
你不觉得他们可能会产生点怀疑吗?
Don't you think they might get a little suspicious?
让我看看
Let me see that.
是银行开出的支票  背书给我
It's a cashier's check. Endorse it over to me.
我不能那么做
No. I couldn't do that.
这张支票是1400美元的
see, this check is for $1,400.
我们谈好的价是1000美元
We agreed upon $1,000.
为什么我不能给你400美元
Why don't I give you back $400
然后你给我那支票呢?
and you give me that check?
那更好
Even better.
这是谁的吗?
Does this belong to anybody?
我是汉莱提  圣诞快乐
This is Handratty. Merry Christmas.
你好  卡尔
Hello, Carl.
喂
Hello.
巴里·艾伦  情报局的
Barry Allen, secret service.
过去几个小时里  我一直在找你
I've been trying to track you down now for the last couple of hours.
你想要怎样?
What do you want?
我想为在洛杉矶发生的事向你道歉
I wanted to apologize for what happened in Los Angeles.
不  不要向我道歉
No, no, you don't apologize to me.
你平安夜也总是在工作吗?
Do you always work on Christmas Eve, Carl?
我自愿...
I volunteered
所以有家的人可以早点回家了
so men with families could go home early.
好像你戴着个结婚戒指来的
Looked like you were wearing a wedding ring
我以为你有家呢
I thought maybe you had a family.
不  我没有家
No. No family.
你想跟我谈谈吗?
You want to talk to me...
- 我们见面谈吧  - 行
- let's talk face-to-face. - All right.
我在斯戴弗桑阿姆斯的办公室  3113房间
I'm at my suite at the stuyvesant Arms, room 3113.
早上我要出发  去拉斯维加斯度周末
In the morning, I leave for Las Vegas for the weekend.
你想再耍我一次吗?
You think you're going to get me again?
你去不了拉斯维加斯
You're not going to Vegas.
你也不在斯戴弗桑阿姆斯
You're not in the stuyvesant Arms.
你想让我在平安夜派20名特工
You'd love for me to send out 20 agents Christmas Eve
冲进你的旅馆  撞开你的门
we barge into your hotel, knock down the door
所以你可以耍我们大家
so you can make fools out of us all.
如果我耍弄了你我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry if I made a fool out of you.
- 真的  - 不需要
- I really am. - Uh-uh, no.
不用  听我说  我是真的
No, listen, I really am.
不  你不要对我有歉意
No, no, you-you do not feel sorry for me.
事实上  我知道是你
The truth is, I knew it was you.
我没有给你戴上手铐  但我知道
Now maybe I didn't get the cuffs on you, but I knew.
人们只知道你告诉他们的  卡尔
Ah, people only know what you tell them, Carl.
那么你告诉我  情报局的巴里·艾伦
Well, then tell me this, Barry Allen, secret service.
你怎么知道我不会看你的钱包?
How did you know I wouldn't look in your wallet?
与杨基队为什么总赢一样的道理
The same reason the Yankees always win.
没有人能把眼睛从条纹衣服上移开
Nobody can keep their eyes off the pinstripes.
杨基对能赢是因为有了米基.曼托
The Yankees win because they have Mickey Mantle.
从来没有人对他们的服装下赌注
No one ever bets on the uniform.
你肯定这点吗  卡尔?
You sure about that, Carl?
我告诉你我能肯定什么
I'll tell you what I am sure of.
你肯定是要被抓住的
You're going to get caught.
这样或是那样  只是个数学问题
One way or another, it's a mathematical fact.
就像在赌城
It's-It's like Vegas.
总是庄家赢
The House always wins.
卡尔  对不起  我得结束谈话了
Well, Carl, I'm sorry, but I have to go.
你打电话不只是为了道歉  对吗?
Ah. You didn't call just to apologize, did you?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
你没别人可打电话
You... you... you have no one else to call.
- 把那个汉堡拿起来  - 好的
- You got that burger up? - Yep.
你好吗?
How are you?
再加点咖啡吗, 先生?
More coffee, sir?
你是收藏家吗?
Are you a collector?
哪方面的?
Of what?
《宇宙之光的俘虏》 《大冻结》
"Captives of the Cosmic Ray," "The Big Freeze"
《金色巨人之地》  我都收集全了
"Land of the Golden Giants." I've got them all.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
巴里·艾伦
Barry Allen.
"闪电"
The Flash.
等等  孩子  过来
Wait, kid, kid, kid.
你指  就像这本漫画书?
You mean like the comic book?
对  就是这漫画书  当他不是"闪电"时
Yeah, the comic book. When he's not The Flash.
巴里·艾伦就是他的名字
That's his name, Barry Allen.
谢谢
Thank you.
听清楚了  他读漫画书!
Now get this: He reads comic books.
漫画书!  巴里·艾伦是"闪电" !
Comic books! Barry Allen is The Flash!
卡尔  慢点儿  我不知道你在说什么
Carl, slow down. I don't know what the hell you're talking about.
他是个孩子  我们的目标是个孩子
He's a kid. Our unsub is a kid.
怪不得我们对不上他的指纹
That's why we couldn't match his prints.
他没有犯罪记录
That's why he doesn't have a record.
联系纽约警察局
Now, I want you to contact NYPD
查一下所有离家出走的年轻人的情况
for every all-points juvenile runaways in New York City.
别忘了飞机场
And don't forget the airports.
他到处洒支票
He's been kiting checks all over the country.
- 为什么是纽约?  - 因为杨基队!
- But why New York? - The Yankees!
他说过杨基队的事情!
He said something about the Yankees!
我们到名单哪儿了?
so where are we on the list?
53号  阿巴戈内尔
Number 53, "Abagnahlee."
早晨好  女士
Good morning, ma'am.
我们是打电话的联邦调查局特工
We're the FBI agents who called.
对  我在等你们  我想你们都饿了
Yes, I've been waiting. I hope you're all hungry.
我正在解冻沙拉丽蛋糕
I put out the sara Lee.
我的丈夫杰克是名律师
My husband Jack is a lawyer.
你的第一任丈夫怎样了 阿巴戈内里太太?
What about your first husband, Mrs. "Abagnahlee"?
阿巴戈内尔  但我喜欢被称为巴恩斯
Abagnale, but I prefer to be called Barnes.
"弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔"
"Frank William Abagnale."
据说他服过役
It says here he was in the service.
你们是在大战时认识的?
Did... Did you two meet during the war?
对  我住的一个很小的村庄里
Yeah, I lived in a very small village
在法国...  叫曼沙
in France... Montrichard.
那种地方的人从来都没听说过沙拉丽
the kind of place where they never heard of sara Lee.
请便
Help yourselves.
没人不喜欢沙拉丽
"Nobody doesn't like sara Lee."
你填写过一份离家出走少年的失踪报告
You filled out a missing person's report for a runaway juvenile
名叫小弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔
by the name of Frank Abagnale Jr.
弗兰克没事吧?
Is Frankie okay?
你知道他在美国大通银行的...
You're aware of the fact that he wrote some checks
死账户上开支票吗?
on a closed account at Chase Manhattan Bank?
知道
Oh, yes.
警察认为他犯了某种罪
The police think he's some type of criminal.
他犯的是重罪  巴恩斯太太
What he did was a felony, Mrs. Barnes.
一共才1000美元
It was $1,000.
像他这么大的孩子有一半在吸毒
Half the kids his age are on dope
向警察扔石子
throwing rocks at police
他们都吓死我了
and they scared me to death
就因为我的儿子犯了个小错误
because my son made a little mistake.
一个17岁的孩子需要吃饭...
Huh. A 17-year-old... boy has to eat
需要有个地方睡觉
has to have a place to sleep.
我们理解  夫人
We understand, ma'am.
有你儿子的照片吗?
Would you happen to have a picture of your son?
有  我有他的旧年册
Oh, yes. I have his old yearbook.
好
Okay.
好  好  我们...
Okay, okay, we, uh...
我们要给所有部门发电传
we need to send out an all-office teletype.
我们的嫌疑犯叫小弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔  17岁!
Our unsub's name is Frank Abagnale Jr., age 17.
弗兰基没事吧?  他有麻烦了吗?
Is Frankie okay? Is he in trouble?
抱歉我得告诉你
Ma'am, I'm sorry to have to tell you:
你儿子在伪造支票
Your son is forging checks.
伪造支票?  等等!
Forging checks? Wait!
我们肯定能赔偿
I'm sure we can take care of that.
我在教堂做半日工
I am working part-time at the church now.
告诉我他欠多少  我还给你们
Just tell me how much he owes and I'll pay you back.
到目前为止  约130万美元
so far, it's about $1.3 million.
梅勒妮  你还好吧?
Hi, Melanie, how are you?
在室内时请用烟灰缸
When you're in the house, please, just use an ashtray.
弗兰克  这奶油真好!
Frank, this fondue is so good!
很好  拿着
Great. Here, take this for me.
好  我喜欢摩埃特!
Ooh, good! I love Moet!
你好吗?
Hey. How are you?
詹姆斯  求你了!
James, James, please!
离那音响远点  好吗?
Just stay away from the hi-fi system, all right?
这是卷轴到卷轴的  你不能那样进带
It's reel-to-reel. You can't wind it like that.
天哪  特里!
Christ! Terry!
这可是意大利的编织!  走路看着点
This is Italian knit! Watch where you're going!
只不过是件衬衫  伙计!
It's just a shirt, man!
弗兰克!  快过来!
Frank! Come quick!
郎斯掉到谈话间里了!
Lance just fell into the conversation pit!
对不起 你知道兰斯·埃坡巴姆在哪儿吗?
Excuse me, you know where Lance Applebaum is?
谢谢
Thank you.
这些瓶子一定要贴上标签!
These bottles need to be labeled when you pick them up.
你知道这有多危险吗?
Do you understand how dangerous this is?
你知道吗?
Do you?
不要只是哭  要点头
Don't stand there crying, just nod your head
跟我说你不再这样了
and tell me you won't do it again.
擦干眼泪  去工作吧
Now dry up and get back to work.
布莱尔医生  布莱尔医生
Dr. Blair, Dr. Blair
薛伍德·布莱尔医生
Dr. Sherwood Blair.
没事吧?
Hey, hey... you okay?
他叫我去采血...
He told me to pick up the blood,
我就做了  但他从没告诉过我要贴标签
so I did, but he never told me to label it.
没关系  别哭了
Hey, it's okay. stop crying.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
- 布伦达  - 布伦达
-Brenda. -Brenda.
布伦达  我不会介意它的
Brenda, I wouldn't worry about it.
那些医生
You know, these doctors
你也知道  他们并不是什么都懂
you know, they don't know everything.
这是我第一周上班
It's my first week
我想他们要解雇我了
and I think they're going to fire me.
不会的  没有人会解雇你的
No, no, nobody's going to fire you, Brenda.
我打赌你会干得很好
I bet you're good at your job.
不  我不会
No, I'm not.
我想如果我求你帮我查一下
Yeah, I bet if I asked you to check on the status
朋友兰斯·埃坡巴姆的状况...
of my friend Lance Applebaum
你会很快帮我做到的
that you could do that for me in a second.
埃坡巴姆先生踝骨骨折
Mr. Applebaum fractured his ankle.
阿什兰德医生在7号检查室给他治疗
Dr. Ashland is treating him in exam room seven.
你看?  没问题吧
You see that? No problem.
这是急诊图表
This is the emergency chart.
看见那个蓝色的星了吗?
see that blue star there?
那表示病人已经被诊断
That means that the patient has been diagnosed.
给他治疗后
And then, after he's been treated
再在这里画个红圈  明白吗?
we put a red circle here, see?
你觉得那些牙套怎么样?
How do you like those braces?
我看它们挺好
I guess they are all right.
我去年把我的摘下来了
I got mine off last year.
天啊  我讨厌它们  只是里边的牙
Boy, I hated them. They were bottoms.
我还得戴我的护牙
You know, I still got to wear my mouth guard.
你的牙确实很好
You have really nice teeth.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
你笑得很美
And you have a pretty smile.
不  我是认真的
No, I mean it.
我真觉得你戴牙套看上去挺好
I really think those braces look good on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
- 布伦达  - 什么?
- Brenda. - Yeah.
这医院有没有在招人?
Do you know if they're hiring here at the hospital?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
你想干什么?
What do you want to do?
我是名医生
I'm a doctor.
亲爱的爸爸...
Dear Dad:
我决定把原来的工作放下一段时间
I've decided to get off the road for awhile.
我找了个医院的夜班工作  遇到了一些不错的人
I've taken a night job at a hospital and met some really nice people.
感觉真好  每天晚上能
Feels good to have my feet on the ground
踏踏实实地睡在同一张床上
to wake up in the same bed every night.
天知道  可能我还要找个人结婚
Who knows, maybe I'll even find someone to settle down with.
"哈佛医学院"...
Harvard Medical school...
全班成绩前茅
top of your class.
"南加州儿童医院"
southern California Children's Hospital.
真是很吸引人的简历  考纳斯医生
Well, that's a pretty impressive resume, Dr. Conners
不幸的是...  我需要的只是...
but unfortunately, uh... the only thing I need
一位夜班急诊室主管
is a... an emergency room supervisor
从半夜到早晨8点的
for my midnight to 8:00am shift
一个照看6名实习生和20名护士的人
someone to baby-sit six interns and 20 nurses
但是...
but, uh...
说到底  我想你会感兴趣的
Hell, I doubt that, uh, you would be interested in that.
过去... 我总是挑选自己的护士
Well, in the past they've always let me choose my own nurses.
考纳利医生
Dr. Connelly?
- 哈里斯医生?  - 在
- Dr. Harris? - Present.
阿什兰医生
Dr. Ashland?
考纳斯医生...
Dr. Conners...
你每天晚上都要检查出勤吗?
You gonna take roll every night?
是的  我要  阿什兰医生
Uh, yes, I will, Dr. Ashland,
如果你要迟到了  我建议你带假条来
and if you're going to be late, I suggest you bring a note.
巴斯曼小姐
Miss Basmann.
梅斯小姐
Miss Mace.
斯特朗小姐
Miss strong.
到
Here.
布朗护士
Nurse Brown.
- 桑福德护士  - 到
-Nurse sanford? - Here.
每4小时30毫克可待因
30 milligrams of codeine every four hours.
每分钟60滴血浆  直到我们算出需要量
Run the plasma at 60 drops a minute until we calculate the fluid requirements.
你估计这烧伤的程度和面积有多少 基达尔?
What do you estimate the degree and extent of the burns, Kildare?
2度和3度烧伤
second and third-degree burns
面积超过皮肤总面积的20%
over about 20 percent of the body surface.
- 你同意吗?  - 我同意
- Do you concur? - I concur.
把他送到小儿科去吧
Let's get him up to Pediatrics.
- 你好 布伦达  - 你好  考纳斯医生
- Hello, Brenda. - Hi, Dr. Conners.
- 你需要在这里签字  - 谢谢
- You need to sign these. - Thank you.
看我有什么变化吗?
Do you notice anything different about me, Doctor?
- 你摘掉牙套了!  - 是的
-You got your braces off! -Yeah!
- 过来  让我看看  - 我整晚都想让你看到!
- Come here. Let me see. - I've been trying to show you all night!
- 真不错  - 是吗?
- Wow. Good job. - Yeah?
摘牙套时痛吗?  我当时感觉很怪异
so, did it hurt when they took them off? Mine felt so weird after.
我总是用舌头磨牙  控制不住!
Mm, I keep rubbing my tongue over them. I can't stop. They're so slippery.
- 感觉很好  是吗?  - 是的  感觉好极了
- It feels good, though, doesn't it? - Yeah, it feels incredible.
天...!
Oh, my.
对不起
I'm... I'm sorry.
考纳斯医生  请到急诊室
Dr. Conners to the ER.
你不去吗?
shouldn't you go?
不去
No. No, no.
急诊病房有位医生  我们继续
They have a staff doctor in the emergency ward. We'll be fine.
他要是正在手术怎么办?
What... what if he's in surgery?
你真的认为我得去?
Do you really think I have to go?
在这里边  考纳斯医生
Oh. In here, Dr. Conners.
先生们  是什么问题?
Gentlemen, what, uh... what seems to be the problem?
脚踏车意外
Bicycle accident.
膝盖骨下大约13厘米处胫骨骨折
Fractured tibia about five inches below the patella.
- 哈里斯医生  - 嗯?
-Dr. Harris. - Yes?
你同意吗?
Do you concur?
同意什么  先生?
C... Concur with what, sir?
同意阿什兰医生刚才说的
With what Dr. Ashland just said.
你同意吗?
Do you... Do you concur?
是个脚踏车意外
Uh... well, it was a bicycle accident.
这孩子说的
Um, the boy told us.
所以你同意?
so you concur?
- 同意?  - 我们应该给他照X光
- Concur? Uh... - I think we should take an X ray,
缝合伤口  再给他打上石膏
then stitch him up and put him in a walking cast.
很好  阿什兰医生  很好
That's very good, Dr. Ashland. Very good.
我看  你们好像不太需要我
Well, you don't seem to have much need for me.
继续
Carry on.
我搞错了  是不是?
I blew it, didn't I?
我为什么没说同意呢?
Why didn't I concur?
请接219分机
Dr.Henning, call extension 219.
接219分机
Dr.Henning, extension 219.
请随便!
Make yourself at home!
老弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔
Frank Abagnale sr.
你不是警察
You're not a cop.
联邦调查局  特工汉莱提
special Agent Handratty, FBI.
你不是警察
You're not a cop.
我的房东说你不是警察
My landlord said you were not a cop.
如果你要拘捕我  我想换件衣服
Well, if you're going to arrest me I'd like to put on a different suit
- 如果可以的话  - 我不是来拘捕你的
- if that's okay with you. - No, no, I'm not here to arrest you.
我是在抓你儿子  他有麻烦了
I'm looking for your son. He's in trouble.
你知道他在哪里吗?
Do you know where he is?
如果我告诉你他在哪里
If I tell you where he is
你能保证不告诉她妈吗?
will you promise not to tell his mother?
能
sure.
弗兰克做了个假身份证
Frank made up a fake I.D.
还参加海军了
and enlisted in the Marine Corps.
他现在在越南
He's over in Vietnam right now.
那孩子现在在地球那头...
That kid is halfway around the world
在该死的丛林里爬行
crawling through the damn jungle
跟共产党打仗  所以...
fighting the Communists, so...
请你  不要到我家来  还说我儿子是罪犯
please, don't come to my home and call my boy a criminal
- 因为这孩子更有出息  - 我没说他是罪犯
- because that kid has more guts... - I never said he was a criminal, Mr. Abagnale.
我说他有麻烦了
I said he was in trouble.
如果你想给我打电话谈谈  这是我电话
If you'd like to give me a call and talk, here's my number.
你一定没有孩子吧?
You're not a father, are you?
你说什么
Pardon me?
如果你也是名父亲的话  你就会明白
If you were a father, you'd know.
我永远不会对我的儿子失望
I would never give up my son.
也永远不会放弃我的儿子
是的  先生  我理解
Yes, sir. I understand.
肖恩  记下这个...
Sean, Sean, now get this:
"河湾公寓
"Riverbend Apartments
乔治亚州  亚特兰大市  兰德欧沃街415号"
415 Landover, Atlanta, Georgia."
乔治亚州  亚特兰大市
Atlanta, Georgia.
我在去机场的路上
Yeah, I'm on my way to the airport.
4小时后和小组会合  再见
I'll meet the team in, uh, in four hours. Bye-bye.
好了  没关系的
Come on, it's okay.
不必哭
You don't have to cry.
对不起!
I'm sorry.
真对不起  弗兰克!
I'm so sorry, Frank.
我不能这么做
I can't do this.
布伦达  听我说
Brenda, listen to me.
我不在乎你是处女
I don't care if you're a virgin, all right?
我可以等
Really, I can wait.
我不是处女
I'm not a virgin.
我2年前做了堕胎手术
I had an abortion two years ago.
我父母找朋友做的
My parents had a friend do it
一个和我父亲一起打高尔夫的人
a man that my father plays golf with.
当我刚恢复好  他们就把我踢出了家门
And then, when I got better, they kicked me out of the house.
我堕过胎  不再是他们的女儿了!
I had an abortion and I wasn't their daughter anymore.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
请不要生我的气
Please don't be mad at me.
求你了  请不要生我的气
Please, please, don't be mad at me.
不  不生气
No, no.
请不要生我的气
Please don't be mad at me.
如果... 我同你父母谈谈怎样?
shh. Now... what if... what if I spoke to your parents, right?
也许能理顺关系
May-Maybe I can straighten things out, huh?
我一直在求他们  但他们还是不让我回家
Well, I ask them all the time but they said I still can't come home.
我爸爸是律师
And my daddy's... a lawyer.
布伦达?
Brenda...
如果你跟一位医生订婚会怎样?
what if you were engaged to a doctor?
那样会不会改变什么?
Will that change anything?
什么?
What?
我去你父母那里...
What if I went to your parents...
同你父亲谈谈...
and I spoke to your father...
求他同意把你嫁给我
and I asked permission to marry you?
是空的
It's empty.
没有人
Nobody here.
考纳斯医生  你是路德教徒吗?
Dr. Conners, are you Lutheran?
是  我是路德教徒
Yes, I-I am a Lutheran,
但是请叫我弗兰克
but, please, call me Frank.
弗兰克  你来祈祷好吗?
Frank, would you like to say grace?
除非你觉得不自在
Unless you're not comfortable.
绝对可以
Absolutely.
两只老鼠掉进奶油桶里
Two little mice fell into a bucket of cream.
第一只老鼠很快放弃  被淹死了...
The first mouse quickly gave up and drowned
但是第二只老鼠拼命努力
but the second mouse, he struggled so hard
把奶油搅拌成黄油
that he eventually churned that cream into butter
它走了出来
and he walked out.
- 阿门  - 阿门
-Amen. -Amen.
阿门  那很美...
Amen. Oh, that was beautiful.
老鼠把奶油搅拌成了黄油
The mouse, he churned that cream into butter.
对
That's right.
- 那很不错  - 谢谢
- That's pretty good. - Thank you.
你有没有决定想在新奥尔良的...
Frank, have you decided which hospital...
哪一家医院工作?
you want to work at here in New Orleans?
说实在的
Well, um, to be quite honest
我在考虑回到法律这行
I'm thinking about getting back into law.
天啊!
Oh, my!
你是医生还是律师?
Are you a doctor or a lawyer?
我去医学院之前 在加州通过了律师考试
Before I went to medical school, I passed the bar in California.
我实习了一年
I practiced law for one year
后来我决定为什么不试试当个儿科医生呢?
then I decided why not try my hand at pediatrics?
你真让人惊奇
You're just full of surprises.
是啊
Yeah.
天呐  医生和律师
Oh, my. A doctor and a lawyer.
布伦达中大奖了
Well, I'd say that Brenda hit the jackpot.
你在哪儿上的法律学校?
Where did you go to law school?
伯克利
Uh, Berkeley.
伯克利  伯克利  天啊!
Berkley, Berkley. Oh, my gosh.
那不是你上学的地方吗  爸?
Isn't that where you went, Daddy?
弗兰克可以帮你工作
Maybe Frank could come work for you, Roger.
你总是说找助理起诉员有多难
You're always saying how hard it is to find Assistant Prosecutors.
他行吗  爸爸?  他行吗  求你了?
Could he, Daddy? Could he, please?
他能为你工作吗?  求你了?
Could he come work with you, please?
你在伯克利念书时
Was that snake Hollingsworth still teaching there
那个狡猾的霍灵斯沃还在教学吗?
when you went through Berkley?
霍灵斯沃
Hollingsworth.
是的  坏脾气的老霍灵斯沃  对吗?
Yes. Grumpy old Hollingsworth, right?
脾气更坏了
I tell you. Meaner than ever.
还有他的狗呢?
And that dog of his?
告诉我  弗兰克  他的狗叫什么名字?
Tell me, Frank, what was the name of his little dog?
对不起
I'm sorry. Uh...
狗死了
The dog was dead.
真是不幸
How unfortunate.
是啊
Yeah.
一个医生  律师  路德教徒...
A doctor, a lawyer, a Lutheran...
那么  你究竟是什么  弗兰克?
so what are you, Frank?
因为你要跟我女儿结婚...
'Cause I think you're about to ask for my daughter's hand in marriage
我有权利知道
and I have a right to know.
知道什么  先生?
Know what, sir?
事实
The truth.
告诉我事实  弗兰克
Tell me the truth, Frank.
你在这儿做什么?
What are you doing here?
像你这样的人在和布伦达做什么?
What is a man like you doing with Brenda?
如果你想要我的祝福
If you want my blessing
如果你想要我的女儿...
if you want my daughter
我想现在就听你说说
I'd like to hear it from you now.
事实是  先生...
The truth is, sir, that...
事实就是...
The truth is that...
我不是医生  也不是律师
I'm not a doctor, I'm not a lawyer...
我也不是飞行员
I'm not an airline pilot.
我什么都不是
I'm... I'm nothing, really.
我只是个爱你女儿的孩子
I'm-I'm-I'm just a kid who's in love with your daughter.
不对
No.
你知道你是什么吗?
You know what you are?
你是个浪漫的人
You're a romantic.
没有我们爱的女人  像我们这样的男人什么都不是
Men like us are nothing without the women we love.
我必须承认  我也为有这样愚蠢的内疚怪念头
I must confess, I'm guilty of the same foolish whimsy.
五次约会后我向卡罗尔求婚...
I proposed to Carol after five dates
口袋空空  一文不名
with two nickels in my pockets and holes in my shoes
因为我知道她就是那个我要找的
because I knew she was the one.
继续向前  弗兰克
so go ahead, Frank.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
提出你想跟我提的吧
Ask the question you came here to ask me.
先生...
sir, uh, uh...
我得做什么?
w-what would I have to do
如果要想在新奥尔良当律师?
to take the bar here in New Orleans?
不  别的问题
No, the... the other question.
穿过那门就是
Right through that door.
祝你好运  考纳斯先生
Good luck, Mr. Conners.
谢谢
Thank you.
1969年12月26日
弗兰克
Hey, Frank...
你知道我一直没明白的是什么吗?
you know what I could never figure out?
你是怎么骗过律师考试的?
How did you cheat on the bar exam in Louisiana?
有什么区别?
Why? What's the difference?
有人替你考试的  有吗?
someone else took the test for you, didn't they?
卡尔  我要被长时间地关在监狱里
Carl, I'm going to prison for a long time.
说真的  知不知道有什么区别?
seriously, what's the difference?
就是个简单的问题
It's a simple question.
你吃那小酶吗?
Are you going to eat that eclair?
是啊  我留着等会儿吃
Yeah. I'm saving it for later.
或者你想分点给我?
Well, you want to split it with me?
不想
No.
把小酶给我一半我就告诉你
Give me half that eclair and I'll tell you.
我早晚会想出来的
I'm going to figure it out sooner or later.
你在菲利浦·利戈比手下工作  负责企业法务
You'll be working under Phillip Rigby in corporate law.
你为什么不搬进来  布置一下办公桌?
Why don't you settle in, organize your desk?
谢谢
Thank you.
我们12点30分与首席检察官和
We're having lunch at 12:30 with the Attorney General
麦克森州长共进午餐
and Governor McKeithen.
- 他本人  - 州长!
- Himself. - The Governor.
我们拼写得正确吗?
Did we spell it right?
非常对
You sure did.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
- 谢谢  先生  - 欢迎你的加入
- Thank you, sir. - Welcome aboard.
看这张照片  斯图尔特先生
Look at this photograph, Mr. Stewart.
这是张普林提斯约克的照片
It's a photograph of Prentice York
就是在那他们发现他死了
where they found him, dead.
这是照片的局部放大
Now, here is an enlargement of part of that photograph.
这是一张被告在作废支票上的签名照片
This is a photograph of the defendant's signature on a canceled check.
这是同一个签名的局部放大
Now, here is an enlargement of that same signature
与...
which matches
他写给西蒙太太的信上的签名相吻合
the signature on the letters that he wrote to Mrs. Simon
这就说明了某种可能性...
which discuss the possibility
说明...  他在路易斯安娜州行骗
of defrauding the great state of Louisiana.
法官大人  陪审团的女士们  先生们...
Your Honor, ladies and gentlemen of the jury
这就是不可辩驳的证据
this is irrefutable evidence
说明被告确实在说谎
that the defendant is, in fact, lying.
考纳斯先生  这是预审
Mr. Conners, this is a preliminary hearing.
没有被告
There is no... defendant.
也没有陪审团
There is no... jury.
只有我
It's just me.
孩子...
son...
你到底怎么了?
what in the hell is wrong with you?!
是米驰吗?
Is that Mitch?
罗杰!  是米驰!
Roger! It's Mitch!
是米驰!
Oh, my, I lost all track of time.
作为今晚"跟着唱"现场嘉宾...
As studio guests for the sing-along tonight
我们邀请了圣莫尼卡教堂的 儿童合唱组
we have the children's choir of st. Monica's Church
他们来自纽约城
in New York City.
纽约城你能加入他们!
Won't you join them and the gang
为爱尔兰唱几首歌吗?  大家一起
in a few songs for the Irish? Everybody!
有人看见过凯莉吗?
Has anybody here seen Kelly?
你来干什么?
What are you doing here?
我来看你
I... I-I came to see you.
你穿成这样干什么?
What are you doing dressed like this?
我找了份政府工作
I took a job. A government job.
你知道我在做什么吗?
You see what I'm doing?
你有没有个好律师?
Do you have a good lawyer?
我现在也算是个律师
Well... I sort of am a lawyer now.
看这封信  税务局想要更多
Look at this letter. The IRs wants more.
我跟他们达成个协议  我交2项罚金
I had a deal with them: two penalties.
他们吃了蛋糕  现在还想要掉下的渣子
They ate the cake, now they want the crumbs.
我想起诉他们
I want to sue them.
现在他们想要渣子
Now they want the crumbs.
他们...  来  坐下
They... Here, sit down.
他们试图吓唬我
They're trying to scare me, intimidate me.
你知道吗?
You know what?
知道什么?  我要让他们追逐我...
You know what? I'll make them chase me...
用他们的余生!
for the rest of their lives.
很高兴看见你  爸爸
Hey, it's great to see you, Daddy.
坐下  我想给你看样东西
Listen, sit down, I... I want to show you something.
我来是要给你这个
I came here to give you this.
这是我的订婚舞会邀请函
It's an invitation to an engagement party.
爸爸  我要结婚了
Daddy, I'm getting married.
你能相信我要结婚了吗?
Can you believe that? I'm getting married.
你现在什么都不用担心了
You don't need to worry about anything now, Dad.
我要有辆崭新的卡迪拉克
Listen, I'm getting a brand-new Cadillac.
我要有栋6万美元的房子...
I'm getting a $60,000 house.
我全得回来了
I'm-I'm getting it all back.
所有的珠宝  毛皮...
All-All the jewelry, all the furs, everything, Dad.
他们拿走的每一样东西  我都要得回来
Everything they took from us, I'm going to get it back.
妈看见你穿成这样了吗?
Now...has Ma seen you dressed like this?
对  她回来取过几个箱子
Yeah, she came to pick up some boxes.
那就好  你知道为什么?
That's okay, that's okay, you know why?
因为她要跟我们一起去参加婚礼
'Cause she... she's going to the wedding with us.
我要给你穿套全新的衣服
I'm going to get you a brand-new suit, Dad.
I'm getting you a brand-new suit.
一套曼哈顿之鹰  带3颗黑色珍珠纽扣
One of those Manhattan Eagle, three-button, black pearl suits.
你会帅极了
You'll look great.
那些是不错  但她不会见我的
Those are nice. Yeah. she won't see me.
你有没有试着给她打电话?
Well, have you tried to call her?
为什么你现在不给她打电话呢?
Why don't... why don't you call her right now?
爸爸  为什么你现在不给她打电话呢?
Dad, why don't you call her right now? Here.
爸  给她打电话  为了我打
Dad, just call her. Call her for me.
打给她  告诉她...
You call her, and you tell her
我有2张头等仓机票  去看她儿子的婚礼...
I have two first-class tickets to go see her son's wedding...
你母亲现在和杰克·巴恩斯结婚了
Your mother's married now, to my friend Jack Barnes.
他们在长岛有套房子
They have a house in Long Island.
联邦调查局来找过我
I had an FBI agent come see me.
你能躲着他们  儿子
You got their number, son.
那家伙很凶
The guy looked scared.
美国政府  亲爱的  吓得不敢照面
The United states government, champ, running for the hills.
乒!  一步登天!
Pow! To the moon!
都结束了
Dad... it's over.
我要洗手不干了
I'm going to stop now.
但是你已经...
But y-you've...
他们永远也抓不住你
They're never going to catch you, Frank.
- 她不该那样做!  - 坐下来好吗?
- Dad, she wouldn't do that. - Why won't you sit down?
她为什么那样做
Why would she do that to you?
过来坐下  喝一杯
Come on, sit with me. Have a drink.
我是你父亲
I'm your father.
那叫我住手吧
Then ask me to stop.
那么叫我住手吧
你不能停
You can't stop.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
好了  你要去哪儿?
Come on, Frank, where are you going?
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
你今晚去哪儿?
Where are you going tonight?
你今晚要去什么奇异的地方?
someplace exotic? Where are you going tonight?
塔西提岛?  夏威夷?
Tahiti, Hawaii?
这是汉莱提
This is Handratty.
你好  卡尔
Hello, Carl.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
你好吗  考纳斯医生?
How are you, Dr. Conners?
我已经有几个月不当考纳斯医生了
Carl, I haven't been Dr. Conners for months now.
平安夜我坐在办公室
Well... I'm sitting here in my office on Christmas Eve.
你想干什么?
What do you want?
好吧
Okay.
我想结束这一切
I want it to be over.
我想结束这一切  因为我要结婚了
Uh... I want it to be over. I'm getting married.
想安顿下来
You know, I'm settling down.
你偷了差不多4百万美元
You've stolen almost $4 million.
你想我们能把这作为结婚礼物给你?
You think we can just call that a wedding present?
这不是件你能躲开的事
Nah, this isn't something you get to walk away from, Frank.
- 我想休战  - 没有休战
- I want to call a truce. - No truce.
你会被抓住  投入监狱
You will be caught, you will go to prison.
你以为后果会是怎样的?
Where did you think this was going?
请放我一马  卡尔
Please leave me alone, Carl.
求你了
Please?
我就快抓住你了  不是吗?
I'm getting close, aren't I?
我接近了所以你害怕了
You're scared because I'm getting close.
我知道...  你在什里夫伯特租了辆车
I know you... you rented that car in shreveport
住在查尔斯湖的一家旅馆
and you stayed in that hotel on Lake Charles.
你想跑  尽管去吧
You want to run, be my guest.
你的支票可不像你那么会说谎
Your checks don't lie as well as you do.
不要追我了
stop chasing me.
我不能停
I can't stop.
这是我的工作
It's my job.
没关系  卡尔
It's okay, Carl.
我只是想我该问一下
I just thought I'd ask, you know?
圣诞快乐
Hey. Merry Christmas, huh?
我爱我的工作
I love my job.
好吧
All right...
我们找来所有的报纸...
let's get every newspaper we can
最近两个月的路易斯安娜州的所有报纸
every newspaper in Louisiana for the last two months.
我们要找什么?
What are we looking for?
结婚声明  以考纳斯的名字
Engagement announcements, name of Conners.
考纳斯?  得了  这孩子现在应该已经...
Conners?! Come on, Carl, the kid would've
已经改名了
changed his name by now.
他不能改
Mm-mm. He can't change it.
她认为他是考纳斯
she thinks he's Conners.
如果他丢了名字  就丢了她
If he loses the name, he loses the girl.
- 恭喜!  - 玩得好吗?
-Congratulations. - You having a good time?
继续跳舞
Keep dancing, huh?
你也一样  谢谢
Oh, me too. Thank you.
我去一下洗手间
I'm going to, uh, the little boys' room.
- 好的  - 好的
-Okay. -Okay.
快点回来
Hurry back.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是联邦调查局的汉莱提特工
I'm Agent Handratty with the FBI.
我们想和主人谈话
We'd like to have a few quiet words
- 如果方便的话  - 我去找他
- with your host, if possible. - I'll get him.
就在那儿  先生
Right over there, sir.
- 你好  罗杰   - 你好
-Hi, Roger. How are you? -Hi, Vin.
晚上好  我是罗杰·斯特朗
Good evening, gentlemen. I'm Roger strong.
卡尔·汉莱提  联邦调查局的
Carl Handratty, FBI.
这是阿姆德斯基和福克斯特工
This is Agents Amdursky and Fox.
抱歉闯到你的舞会
sorry to crash your party, sir.
没关系  我能为你做什么?
Not at all. What can I do for you?
如果不太麻烦  我想见新郎
If it's not too much trouble, I'd like to meet the groom.
有什么问题吗?
Is there a problem?
弗兰克!  弗兰克!
Frank! Frank!
你能拿一下这些支票吗?
Can you hold all these?
好的  来这边
Yeah. Come here.
这些支票是我父亲的朋友送的
They're checks. They're from my dad's friends.
是送给我们用来开始新生活...
They're for us, so we can start a new life... Hey!
你要干什么?  怎么了?
What are you doing? What's wrong?
- 我们得离开  - 什么?!
- We have to leave. - What?!
- 布伦达  你爱我  是吧?  - 是的
- Brenda, you love me, right? - Yes.
- 我是说  无论怎样你都会爱我  - 是的
- I mean, you'd love me no matter what. - Yes.
我是说  无论我生病
I mean, you'd love me
还是贫穷  或者甚至...
whether I was sick or whether I was poor
有另外一个名字  你都会爱我
or even if I had a different name.
弗兰克  你从哪儿弄来的那些钱?
Frank, where'd you get all that money?
布伦达  听我说   名字并不重要  对吗
Brenda, listen. A name, right? A name, it doesn't matter.
我叫弗兰克·考纳斯  对吧?
My name is Frank Conners, right?
- 那是跟你一起时用的名字  - 对
- That's who I am with you. - Yes.
但我们都有秘密  有时旅行时...
But-but we all have secrets. You know, sometimes when I travel
我用弗兰克·泰勒这名字  这是我的秘密
I use the name Frank Taylor. That-That's my secret.
- 弗兰克·泰勒?  - 是的  弗兰克·布莱克
-Frank Taylor?! -Yeah, Frank Taylor, you know?
- 弗兰克·布莱克  - 弗兰克·布莱克?!
-Frank Black. -Frank Black?!
- 是的  这没关系  - 你为什么说这些?
- Yeah, it doesn't matter. - Why are you saying all this?
布伦达  我不想再跟你说谎
Brenda... Brenda, I don't want to lie to you anymore.
好吗?  我不是医生
All right? I'm not a doctor.
从来没上过医学院
I never went to medical school.
我不是律师  不是哈佛毕业生  也不是路德教徒
I'm not a lawyer or a Harvard graduate or a Lutheran.
布伦达  我1年半前从家里跑出来
Brenda, I ran away from home a year and a half ago
那时16岁时
when I was 16.
弗兰克...
Frank...
弗兰克?
Frank?
你不是路德教徒?
You're not a Lutheran?
布伦达  看见这些钱了吗?
Brenda... you see all this money?
看见这些钱了吗?  我还有
You see all this money? I have more.
我还有更多
I have plenty more.
我有的是钱
I have enough money
足够我们两个下半辈子用了
to last us for the rest of our lives
看
Look.
别逗我了!
Frank, stop teasing me.
你是弗兰克·考纳斯  28岁
You're Frank Conners. You're Frank Conners, and you're 28 years old and...
- 布伦达  - 你为什么对我说谎?
- Brenda... - Why would you lie to me?
- 布伦达  布伦达...   - 我想知道你的名字
-Brenda  Brenda... - I want to know your name.
- 听我说  布伦达  - 告诉我你的名字
-Listen to me, Brenda. -Tell me your name.
我们可以住在任何想住的地方
We can live anywhere we want
但是你得信任我  布伦达
but you have to trust me, Brenda.
- 你信任我吗?  - 是的
- Do you trust me? - Yes.
- 你爱我吗  布伦达?  - 我爱你
- Do you love me, Brenda? - Yes.
- 你爱我?  - 我爱你
- You love me? - I love you.
打断一下  孩她妈
Excuse me, Mother.
这是汉莱提先生  我太太  卡罗尔
Honey, this is Mr. Handratty. My wife Carol.
- 汉...   - 汉莱提  夫人
-Oh, Mister...? -Handratty, ma'am.
- 莱提  - 是的
-Ratty. - Yes.
你看见弗兰克或布伦达了吗?
Have you seen Frank or Brenda?
我想他们上楼了
I-I think they went upstairs.
弗兰克...
Frank...
布伦达  过来
Brenda, come here.
2天后  我们在...
Okay, in two days, you're going to meet me
在迈阿密国际机场见面   好吗?
at Miami International Airport, all right?
你父母睡觉后离开家
You're going to leave the house after your parents go to sleep.
搭出租车
You're going to take a taxicab.
把这钱给出租司机
You give the taxi driver this money right here
告诉他整夜开
and you tell him to drive all through the night.
布伦达  你将在上午10点离开
Brenda, you're going to leave at 10:00am.
- 上午10点  好吗?  - 但是...
- 10:00am, all right? - But...
那间屋子  先生?
Which room, sir?
拐角那间
In the corner.
听我说  好吗?
You have to listen to me, all right?
迈阿密国际机场到站口
The International Terminal in Miami, all right?
- 重复一遍  - 迈阿密国际机场到站口
- Say it. - Okay, the International Terminal in Miami.
- 不管怎样  - 不管怎样
-No matter what... - No matter what...
- 搭出租车  - 我会的
-You're going to take a taxicab. - I will take a taxi.
上午10点到那儿
You're going to be there at 10:00am.
我会到那儿的  不管怎样
I will be there at 10:00am, no matter what.
- 2天后  - 2天
-In two days. -Two days.
2天  布伦达  2天
Two days, Brenda. Two days.
不管怎样两天后上午10点  我会到那儿
In two days, I'll be there no matter what, at 10:00am.
我们不会告诉任何人
You're not going to tell anyone, Brenda.
答应我
You have to promise me, now.
弗兰克  求你!
Frank, please!
你走之前请告诉我你的名字
Before you go, please tell me your name.
请告诉我
Please, tell me.
小弗兰克·威廉·阿巴戈内尔
Frank William Abagnale Jr.
国际航班
National Airlines
27号班机  途径萨拉索塔  坦帕
flight number 27, serving Fort Myers, sarasota, Tampa
终点纽约肯尼迪机场  现在正在检票...
and New York Kennedy, is now available at gate n...
14号通道
skycap, Gate 14. skycap, Gate 14.
出租车!
Taxi!
请您注意...
Your attention...
布伦达
Brenda.
那家伙没有出现  肯定是在耍咱们
This guy's a no-show. He must've got wise to us.
也许走漏了消息  今天不来明天也会来的
Maybe he was tipped. If he's not here today, he'll be tomorrow.
出国之前我们一定会抓到他.
We'll get him before he leaves the country.
他没有护照
He doesn't have a passport.
过去的半年里他去过了哈佛和伯克利
For the last six months, he's gone to Harvard and Berkeley.
我敢打赌他已经弄到了护照
I'm betting he can get a passport.
所以我们必须在迈阿密机场全神戒备
so we have all our men waiting for him here in Miami International.
这个机场他以前来过  了解这里的出口
He's used it before. He knows the layout.
我已经和迈阿密警方联系过他们会协助我们
I talked to Miami police; they've offered us
50名便衣警察会轮班盯防
50 uniformed cops in two shifts of 25.
我们的人现在在机场的已经有100多个了
With our guys, that's almost 100 men in one airport.
你觉得我们是不是应该通知其他地方?
Don't you think we should spread it around?
不  这里是他的逃离点
No, no, this is the exit point.
你怎么知道他不会租一辆汽车
Well, how do you know he hasn't rented a car
然后跑到纽约或者亚特兰大的机场
and driven to airports in New York, Atlanta?
因为我不在纽约  也不在亚特兰大
Because I'm not in New York. I'm not in Atlanta.
我是弗兰克·罗伯茨
Yes, this is, uh, Frank Roberts
我将在本地区的大学里巡回演讲
and I'm letting all the universities
来让大家了解到泛美航空的...
in the area know that Pan Am will be initiating
本年度最新的招聘计划
a new recruiting program this year.
明早我将在贵校结束行程
I'II, uh, be stopping by your campus tomorrow morning.
感谢你们的到来
Thank you all very much for coming.
今天结束的时候
At the end of the day
我将选择八名年轻女士...
I'll be choosing eight young ladies to be a part of...
做为泛美未来的空中小姐
Pan Am's future stewardess flight crew program.
同时这八位女士将陪同我
Now, these eight young ladies will accompany me
去欧洲进行两个月的巡回演讲
on a two-month public relations tour through Europe.
途中她们将学习到
They will discover firsthand what it takes
如何成为泛美航空的一流空姐
to be a Pan American stewardess.
给我最少两个兄弟...
Give me at least two men...
两个通道最少要有一个人
Nah, one man per every two counters.
可以吗
All right?
- 阿姆德斯基?  - 嗯?
- Amdursky? - Yeah?
保证你的人  守着人行道和出入口
Make sure your uniforms are covering the sidewalk entrances and exits.
我们来经常巡查男洗手间
Hey... let's have, uh, periodic sweeps of the men's lav.
你  负责这里
You, here.
什么条件使我能成为未来的空中小姐?
What qualifies me to be a future stewardess?
我认为我真的很友善
Well, I think that I'm really friendly
真能帮助人...
and I can really help out
使人感到在飞机上受到欢迎  并且...
and, um, make people feel welcome on the plane and...
我们在90米的高度上
We'll be traveling at 6,000 miles per hour
以9600公里时速飞行
at an altitude of 300 feet.
我行装已打好  我准备好出发
All my bags are packed, I'm ready to go...
依琳娜·安德森
Ilene Anderson.
米姬·埃克
Miggy Acker.
曼布拉·乔·麦克米伦
Debra Jo McMillan.
坎迪·赫斯顿
Candy Heston.
你看见走在最前面的金发妞了吗?
You see that blonde out front?
- 我本该成为一名飞行员的  - 很对
- I should have been a pilot. - Exactly.
汉莱提先生
Mr. Carl Handratty
请接听免费电话
please pick up the courtesy telephone.
汉莱提
Handratty.
卡尔  你的对讲机刚才不好使
Carl, your walkie-talkie wasn't working.
有一个穿泛美制服的人
There's a guy in a Pan Am uniform
坐在大都市单排座车到站口J
sitting in a white Coupe DeVille out in front of Terminal J.
那是包机口
That's the charter terminal.
你看见他的脸了吗?
Can you get a look at his face?
他带着飞行员的帽子
He's got his pilot's cap on.
卡尔  我想是他
Carl, I think it's him!
从车里出来  弗兰克
Out of the car, Frank.
弗兰克?
Frank?!
从车里出来
step out of the car!
把手放在我能看见的地方别动
Keep your hands where I can see 'em.
不要开枪  我只是个司机
Don't shoot me! I'm just a driver.
一个人给我100美元让我穿这制服...
A man paid me $100 to wear this uniform
- 到飞机场接人  - 你接谁?
- and pick someone up at the airport. - Who you picking up?
接汉莱提
收队  我们走
Pack up, let's fly away.
七个月后
南美洲  澳大利亚
South America, Australia
新加坡  埃及
Singapore, Egypt.
这家伙完全失去疯了
The kid's gone completely out of control.
- 为什么没通知我?  - 谁也没通知  长官
- Why wasn't I called? - Nobody was called, sir.
银行直到上周才知道
The banks didn't know what was happening till last week.
不可能
That's impossible.
他们没通知是因为这不是伪造
They didn't call 'cause it's not counterfeiting.
- 反正是其他的事  - 到底是什么呢?
- It's something else. - Well, what is he doing?
他做的是真支票
He's making real checks, sir.
很完美...  航空公司辨别不出来
These are so perfect the airline didn't know the difference.
上张支票是在一周前在马德里兑现的
Last check was cashed in Madrid a week ago.
我猜他还在那儿  我们现在就得出发
My guess is he's still there. We have to leave now, sir. Today.
去哪?  西班牙?  你想去西班牙?
Go where? Spain? You want to go to spain?
最后他会回去的...  回到印支票的地方
Well, eventually, he's got to go back to where the checks were printed.
这就是他为什么在欧洲活动
I think that's why he's moving back through Europe.
看着这地图  先生  他在做一个圈子
Look at the map, sir. He's making a circle.
他要用完支票了  我可能说得不准
He's running out of checks. I know it's a... it's a long shot, sir
但如果我们从马德里开始追踪他
but if we track him from Madrid,
- 还是能抓住他的  - 如果你在这儿抓不住他
- sir, we could still catch him. - I'm sorry, Carl, if you couldn't catch him here
那在别的地方也抓不住
you're not going to catch him there.
可是我们就让他跑掉吗
But, sir, we're going to let him get away.
卡尔  是你让他跑掉的
No, Carl, you let him get away.
完美的边界尺寸...  整个一圈
A perfect one-16th all the way around.
上色毫无瑕疵
Color separation is flawless.
墨迹没有流淌
There's no bleeding. Hmm.
在美国没有人能干得这么好
Nobody does work like this in the states.
除了我们
Nobody but us.
是在哪儿印制的?
Where was it printed?
- 是在一个老印刷机上  - 老印刷机
- It was printed on a monster... - A monster.
- 海德尔堡  伊斯的利亚半岛  - 海德尔堡
- a Heidelberg, an Istra... - Heidelberg.
过时的  4色的
a dinosaur, four colors.
能感觉出印刷机的重量
You can smell the weight.
2吨  不算墨水
Two tons, without the ink.
他们在哪儿做这样的印刷?
Where do they do printing like this?
德国  英国...
Germany, Great Britain...
- 法国  - 法国!
- France. - France!
弗兰克的母亲提过法国一个村子的名字
France. Frank's mother said the name of a village in France
那儿没有沙拉利
where they didn't have sara Lee.
她遇见弗兰克父亲的村子
The village where she met Frank's father.
我记不得...
Oh, yeah, I don't remember, uh...
以"M"开头  是"曼"什么的
It started with an M. It was, uh, "Mont" something.
- 福克斯先生?  - 对  对
- "Mont." Mr. Fox? - Uh, yes, yes.
提问: "你是在大战时遇见你丈夫的"
Question: "You met your husband during the war?"
- "我住在法国一个村庄  - 就是这么说的
- "Yes, I lived in a small village in France. - Yeah, right.
"在那儿人们从没听说过沙拉利"
"The kind of place where they never heard of sara Lee."
告诉我你记下了那个村子的名字
Tell me you wrote down the name of the village, Mr. Fox.
曼沙
Montrichard.
卡尔!
Carl? Carl!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
我们总是在圣诞节交谈感觉怎么样?
How is it that we're always talking on Christmas, Carl?
每个圣诞节  我都跟你交谈!
Every Christmas I'm talking to you!
穿上衣服  弗兰克  你被捕了
Put your shirt on, Frank. You're under arrest.
你饿了吗?  想要些豆子吗?
Hey, are you hungry? Do you want some beans, Carl?
他们这儿有法国最好的豆子
They got the best French beans here.
- 来尝尝  - 外面有20多名法国警察
- Here, give these a try. - There's two dozen French police officers outside.
- 卡尔  真的很美味  - 他们想抓你
- Carl, I gotta tell you, they're delicious. - They wanted to bring you in.
- 想尝一口吗?  - 但他们需要美国人的帮助
- You want a bite? - But they needed the help of an American.
你饿了吗?  想尝一口吗?
Are you hungry? You want a bite?
但我说了我不把他们带到你这里来
But I told them I wouldn't bring them to you
除非我能亲自给你戴上手铐
unless I could put the cuffs on you myself.
你有枪吗?  你有枪吗?
Well, you have a gun? You have a gun?
- 没有?  - 没有
-No gun? -No.
没枪
No gun.
那你在跟我说什么?
And-and you're... and you're telling me what?
在外面有20多名法国警察?
there's two dozen French police officers out there
就在平安夜?  你是那么说的吗?
right now on Christmas Eve? That's what you're telling me?
- 对  - 好吧  好吧
- Yeah. - All right, all right.
这里没有窗户
Well, there's no windows here.
- 我到前门看看  - 不!  不!
- I'm going to take a look out the front door. - No! No!
我告诉他们我先走出去给他们一个信号
I told them I'd walk out first and give a signal.
- 给  你自己戴上  - 不  我不戴
- Here, you can put these on yourself. - No, I can't do that! I can't do that.
你知道为什么?
You know why?
因为你总是很蠢
'Cause I think you're full of shit.
我看外面一个人也没有
I don't... I don't think there's anyone else out there.
我看只有你和我
I think... I think it's just me and you.
对  只有你和我  你知道吗?
That's right. I think it's just me and you, and you know what?
你得自己抓住我
You're going to have to catch me yourself!
我们没时间争论了
I wo... we don't have time for this.
很好  很好
Ah, that's good. That's good.
告诉我你想让我看见什么
Tell me what you want me to see, huh?
我不会对你撒谎的
I wouldn't lie to you.
你戴着结婚戒指
Look, you're wearing a wedding ring.
你戴着结婚戒指  卡尔!  这事你骗我了!
You're wearing a wedding ring, Carl! You lied to me about that!
是不是撒谎了?
Didn't you lie about that?!
你问我是不是有个家
You asked me if I had a family.
过去有  但不再有了
I did, but I don't anymore.
有问题吗?  不  没有问题
Yes? No, no, no, there is no problem.
我们马上出来
We're coming out right now.
干得不错  干得不错
Whoa, that was good. That was good.
你是不是给旅馆前台服务员钱
What, did you... you pay some hotel desk clerk
让他给你打那个电话?  是你干的吧?
to make that call for you, is that what you did?
是卢克警官
It was Captain Luc.
我还有1分钟带你出去
I've got one minute to bring you out.
卢克警官?  卢克警官!
Captain Luc? Captain Luc!
卢克警官
Ooh, Captain Luc.
卡尔  我得说  听起来很像那么回事
Well, Carl, I gotta say that-that sounds pretty official to me
但是像我说的...  我看只有...
but like I said, I... I think it's just
我和你在这  只有我们俩
me and you here, it's me and you.
所以你得来抓我
so you're going to have to catch me.
弗兰克  弗兰克  这件事你得相信我
Frank. Frank! You have to trust me on this!
这些人感到难堪  他们很生气
These people have been embarrassed, Frank. They're angry.
你抢了他们的银行  偷了他们的钱
You rob their banks, you steal their money
生活在他们的国家
you live in their country.
我告诉过你会这样的
I told you this was what was going to happen
没有其它了结方式
that there was no other way for it to end.
不要胡来
Don't make a mistake!
很好
That's good.
很好  卡尔  你知道吗?
That's good, Carl, you know?
接着编
Keep pushing that lie.
接着编直到编成真的
Keep pushing till you make it true.
他们会杀了你
They're going to kill you!
如果你走出那门  他们会杀了你
You walk out that door, they're going to kill you.
是真的吗?
Is that the truth?
真的
Yeah.
你有孩子吗?  卡尔?
You have any children, Carl?
有个4岁的女儿
I have a four-year-old daughter.
你以女儿发誓?
You swear on your daughter?
你发誓?
You swear?
好极了  卡尔
That was really good, Carl.
他由我监护
I have him in custody.
我控制住他了!
I got him.
我控制住他了!  没关系!
I got him! It's all right!
没关系!  我控制住他了!
It's all right! I got him!
我想做官方纪录
Hey, I want it... I want it on the record.
弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔自愿被捕
Frank Abagnale surrendered of his own accord.
明白吗?  明白吗?
Understood? Understood?
你们要把他带哪里去?  我应该跟着
Where are you taking him? I'm... I'm supposed to go.
你们要把他带哪里去?
Where are you taking him?
让我上...!  让我上车!
Let me in the... Let me in the car!
让我上车!
Hey! Let me in the car!
不要担心  弗兰克
Don't worry, Frank!
我会把你引渡回美国的  别担心
I'll have you extradited back to the United states. Don't worry.
卡尔
Carl...
卡尔  你得记着
Carl, you have to remember
我们一落地就让我给父亲打电话
to let me call my father when we land.
我只是想在他从电视
I just want to, I want to talk to him
或什么上看见我之前跟他谈谈
before he sees me on television or something like that.
卡尔  看
Carl, look.
- 44号跑道  - 弗兰克  你父亲死了
- Runway 4-4. - Frank, your father is dead.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
在快到家之前我什么都不想说
I didn't want to say anything till we got closer to home.
他在赶火车时  从大中心车站掉下台阶
He-He... He fell down some steps at Grand Central station trying to catch a train.
我本不想亲自告诉你
I didn't want to be the one to tell you.
你骗我的  是吗?
You're lying, right?
你说过我可以跟他交谈
You said I could talk to him.
卡尔  你怎么敢  你怎么敢说那样的话?
Carl, who are you to... who are you to say something like that, huh?
你怎么敢说那样的话?
Who are you to say something like that?
- 你说过我可以跟他交谈  - 他掉下去
- You said I could talk to him. - He fell, and he...
摔断了脖子  我很难过
and he broke his neck. I'm sorry.
我真的很难过
I'm really sorry.
见鬼!
Goddamn it!
卡尔  我要吐了!
Carl, I'm going to be sick!
- 没关系的  没事的  - 卡尔  我要去卫生间
- It's all right. It's all right. It's okay. - Carl, I got to go to the bathroom.
- 我要吐了  - 当然  去卫生间吧
- I'm going to be sick. - Sure. Let's go in the bathroom.
见鬼!
Goddamn it!
爸爸
Oh, Daddy...
各位  请回到座位上
You'll have take your seat, sir.
我告诉过你2次了  要着陆了
I've told you twice. We're landing.
- 对不起  谢谢  - 你们全部
- Sorry. Thank you... - All of you.
弗兰克!  出来了
Frank! Come on now.
- 弗兰克?  - 我们6分钟后着陆
- Frank? - We're landing in six minutes.
你们得回到座位...
All of you need to be in your seats
- 系上安全带  - 弗兰克!  开门!
- With your seat belts fastened. - Frank, open the door!
弗兰克!
Frank!
- 你来  - 好
- You do it. - Yeah.
弗兰克!  弗兰克!
Frank! Frank!
好  请大家坐着别动
All right, remain seated, everyone, please.
- FBI  坐着别动  - FBI  坐着别动
- FBI. Stay seated. - FBI. Stay seated.
- 请坐好  - 坐好
-Please remain seated! -Stay seated.
你必须坐好  直到飞机停稳
You must stay seated until the aircraft has come to a complete stop.
天啊
God almighty.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
把手放在脑后!
Hands behind your head!
卡尔  请让我上车吧
Carl, get me in the car, please.
让我上车吧
Get me in the car.
让他上车
Put him in.
鉴于罪行的严重性...
Taking into account the gravity of these crimes
放肆和逃避的行为...
your history of bold and elusive behavior
及对美国法律的蔑视
and your complete lack of respect for the laws of the United States
我不得不驳回你  将你作为少年犯对待的请求
I have no choice but to ignore your request to be treated as a minor
判你在亚特兰大监视最严密的监狱服刑12年
and sentence you to 12 years in Atlanta's maximum security prison
并强烈建议对你在整个服刑期间
and recommend strongly that you be kept in isolation
进行隔离关押
for the entirety of that sentence.
走那边的门
Use that door over there.
替我向大家问好
and give everyone my love.
我一直都在想他们
I think about them all the time.
圣诞快乐  弗兰克
Merry Christmas, Frank.
我给你带来了几本漫画书
Hey, I got you some comic books here.
你女儿怎样?
How's your daughter?
- 她叫什么名字?  - 格雷斯
- What was her name? - Grace.
我不知道
Well... I don't know.
她跟母亲在芝加哥生活
she lives with her mother in Chicago
我不常见她
and I don't get to see her much.
箱子里是什么?
What's in the briefcase?
我是在去机场的路上
Oh. I'm on my way to the airport.
是个在明尼苏达州活动的伪造支票者
It's a paperhanger who's working his way through Minnesota.
他  他搞得我们发疯
Aw, geez, he's... he's driving us crazy.
你带支票来了吗?
You got any of the checks?
对  我带了张他在...
Yeah, yeah, I got a... a counterfeit that he drew
大湖储贷银行填写的假支票
on the Great Lakes savings and Loan.
他使用一台模版机  和一台"木下"牌打字机
see, he's just using a stencil machine and an Underwood.
- 伪造者是名银行出纳  - 什么?
- Yeah, it's a teller at the bank. - Say again?
肯定是出纳  卡尔
I-It's definitely a teller, Carl.
银行从来都是用手工封盖日期
I mean, banks, they always use hand-stamps for the dates, see.
一遍遍使用  所以总有磨损
They get used over and over again so they always get worn out
数字总是有断点
and the numbers are always cracking.
6和9  你看  它们先磨损
The sixes and the nines... see, they go first.
谢谢
Thanks.
我想让你帮我看样东西
I'd like you to take a look at something for me.
告诉我你是怎么想的
Tell me what you think.
这是假的
That's a fake.
你还没看呢  怎么知道?
How do you know? You haven't looked at it.
没有剪开的边
Well, there's no perforated edge, right?
我是说  这张支票是手工裁的 不是从大张上剪下的
I mean, this... this check was hand-cut, not fed.
没错
Yeah...
纸是双层的
Paper is double-bonded
作为银行支票太重了
much too heavy to be a bank check.
这磁墨  我能用手感觉到它的凸起
Magnetic ink, it's, uh, raised against my fingers
应该是平的
instead of flat.
并且闻起来不像支票专用墨
And this doesn't smell like MICR.
是一种...  一种画图用墨
It's some kind of a... you know, some kind of a drafting ink.
在文具店能买到这种墨
You know, the kind you get at a stationery store.
弗兰克
Frank.
有没有兴趣在联邦调查局经济犯罪科工作?
would you be interested in working with the FBI's Financial Crimes Unit?
我在这里已经有工作了  送信
I already got a job here. You know, I, uh, deliver the mail.
弗兰克  我们能把你从监狱里放出来
Frank, we have the power to take you out of prison.
你将在联邦调查局的监护下
You'd be placed in the custody of the FBI
服完剩下的刑期
where you'd serve out the remainder of your sentence
作为联邦政府的雇员
as an employee of the federal government.
在谁的监护下?
Under whose custody?
我叫弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔
Hi. I-I'm Frank Abagnale.
我应该今天开始工作
I'm supposed to start work here today.
是个安排英国处女岛度假的旅游公司
It's a tour company operating out of the BVI.
先生  阿巴戈内尔来了
sir, Mr. Abagnale is here.
我会再打给你
I'm going to call you back.
你好  卡尔
Hello, Carl.
欢迎来到联邦调查局
Welcome to the FBI.
我带你看看工作的地方
I'll show you where you're working.
卡尔  我要在这里工作多久?
Carl... how long do I have to work here?
早上8点15分到晚上5点钟
It's 8:15 in the morning to 5:00 in the afternoon.
午休45分钟
45 minutes for lunch.
不是问这个
No, I...
我是说  多久?
I mean, how long?
每天
Every day.
每天  直到我们放你走
Every day, Frank, till we let you go.
- 什么事  - 卡尔
- Yeah. - Hey, Carl.
- 进展如何  - 现在聊天不合适  弗兰克
- How you doing? - It's not a good time, Frank.
我在为周末赶工
I'm clearing my desk for the weekend.
介意我明天来跟你一起工作吗?
Carl, you mind if I come to work with you tomorrow?
明天是星期六
Tomorrow is saturday.
我要飞到芝加哥看我女儿
I'm flying to Chicago to see my daughter.
星期一回来
I'll be back to work on Monday.
去见格雷斯?
You're going to see Grace, huh?
对  是我的计划
Well, that's the plan.
星期一前我该干什么?
so what should I do till Monday?
对不起  这我帮不了你  让一让
I'm sorry, kid, I can't help you there. Excuse me.
汉莱提
This is Handratty.
好  接过来
Oh, yeah, put him on.
斯耶先生
Mr. Sawyer.
你怎么样
How are you?
我还有6张的支票
I have a half a dozen more checks
关于那家英国处女岛旅游公司的
on that tour operator at the BVI.
请乘坐美国航空 355航班...
American Airlines 355...
飞往芝加哥和旧金山的...
serving Chicago and san Francisco...
旅客准备登机
is now open for passenger check-in.
你怎么办到的  弗兰克?
How'd you do it, Frank?
你是怎么通过路易斯安娜州的律师考试的?
How'd you pass the bar in Louisiana?
你来这干什么?
What are you doing here?
听着
Listen...
我很抱歉给你惹了这么多麻烦
I'm sorry I put you through all this.
你要是回到欧洲  会死在坡皮监狱的
You go back to Europe, you're gonna die in Perpignan Prison.
如果你想从美国逃跑
You try to run here in the states
我们就会把你送回亚特兰大关50年
we'll send you back to Atlanta for 50 years.
我知道
I know that.
我花了4年时间设法把你放出来
I spent four years trying to arrange your release.
我得向我的老板
Had to convince my bosses at the FBI
和首席检察官证明
and the Attorney General of the United states
你不会逃跑
you wouldn't run.
你为什么那样做呢?
Why'd you do it?
- 你是个孩子  - 我不是你的孩子
- You're just a kid. - I'm not your kid.
你说你要去芝加哥
You said you were going to Chicago.
我女儿这个周末不能见我了
My daughter can't see me this weekend.
她要去滑雪
she's going skiing.
你说她4岁
You said she was four years old.
你撒谎
You're lying.
我离开时她4岁
she was four when I left.
现在15岁了
Now she's 15.
我太太再婚11年了
My wife's been remarried for 11 years.
我有时见格雷斯
I see Grace every now and again.
- 我不明白  - 你当然明白
- I don't understand. - Sure you do.
有时说谎更容易
sometimes it's easier living the lie.
我今晚让你飞走  弗兰克
I'm going to let you fly tonight, Frank.
我甚至不会拦你的
I'm not even going to try to stop you.
因为我知道  你星期一会回来
That's 'cause I know you'll be back on Monday.
是吗  你怎么知道我会回来?
Yeah? How do you know I'll come back?
看
Look.
弗兰克
Frank.
没有人在追你
nobody's chasing you.
前往匹兹堡的
American Airlines flight 131
美航131航班  已开始登机
to Pittsburgh is now ready for boarding.
持登机牌的乘客  请到23A门
Passengers with boarding passes, please proceed to Gate 23A.
好的
Okay.
爱丽丝  他还没来电吗?
Alice, has he still not called?
是的  还没有
No, he hasn't.
早上好
Good morning.
我召开此次会议是为了讨论
I've, uh, called this meeting to discuss
一种新型的支票欺诈和伪造手段
a new type of check fraud and counterfeiting
嫌疑犯涂改支票
which the unsub is washing and altering checks
然后发送到亚利桑那州
then passing them throughout Arizona.
这个嫌疑犯是个大赌徒
This unsub is a big dog
支票填5位数
passing checks as large as five figures.
对不起  我迟到了
sorry I'm late.
抱歉
sorry.
瑞特特工的桌子上有张伪造的支票
We have a recovered check on Agent Reiter's desk.
我们出去看看吧
Why don't we step out to the bullpen?
每一行都被加重
There's impressions on every line.
好像原来数额是60美元
Looks like the original amount was for $60.
我能看一下吗?
Mind if I take a look?
一周前在福莱格斯达福兑现的
Cashed in Flagstaff a week ago.
银行损失1万6千美元
Cost the bank $16,000.
- 是张真支票  - 对
- It's a real check. - Yeah.
被洗过了
Yeah. It's been washed.
原来的东西只剩下签名
The only thing original is the signature.
但是很完美  卡尔  真的
But it's perfect, Carl. I mean...
它不是用酸洗或漂白的
I mean this isn't hydrochloride or bleach.
不是
No.
是什么新东西
something new.
也许是一种指甲膏清洗剂或者丙酮
Maybe a nail polish remover where the acetone
之类的东西洗去手写墨水
removes the ink that's not been printed?
你是怎么做的?  弗兰克?
How did you do it, Frank?
你是怎么骗过路易斯安娜州的律师考试的?
How did you cheat on the bar exam in Louisiana?
我没作弊
I didn't cheat.
我学了两周就通过了
I studied for two weeks and I passed.
是真的吗?  弗兰克?
Is that the truth, Frank?
是真的吗?
Is that the truth?
我肯定这家伙从邮箱里偷支票
I'll bet this guy steals checks out of mailboxes.
他洗掉他们的名字  换成自己的
He washes off their names and he puts on his own.
你说他是当地人?
You're saying that he's a local?
如果是我的话
Well, if it were me, you know
我会先给银行打电话  查一下余额...
I'd call the bank first, I'd check out the balance...
弄清楚有足够的钱在里面
Make sure there's enough money in there
- 确定值得冒险  - 正是如此
- to make it worth your while. - Exactly.
卡尔  我想这家伙非常狡猾
You know, Carl, I think this guy's pretty smart.
我想现在我们要做的就是去抓住他
I guess all we have to do now is catch him.
小弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔已经结婚26年
那就是今早的第一件事
We'll start first thing in the morning.
我们开始追查这个名叫埃里克·安东尼家伙
We'll run the name Eric Anthony Feeders.
有三个儿子  在中西部过着平静的生活
在内华大  亚利桑那  加利福尼亚各州
In Nevada, Arizona, California.
所有的名字  是吗?  克里斯·弗兰克也要注意?
Both names, right? Chris Frank, too?
自从1974年出狱后
没错...
Yeah...
弗兰克帮助FBI抓住了一些世界上隐藏最深的支票造假者
被认为是世界上最著名的反银行诈骗和欺诈专家
弗兰克还设计了银行和
世界500强公司每天都在使用的安全支票
这些公司每年向小弗兰克·阿巴戈内尔
支付几百万美元的服务费用
弗兰克和卡尔至今仍然是好友